<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>IWU Spectrum</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com</link>
	<description>News and events in the IWU Community</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2014 12:16:39 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=3.9.3</generator>
	<item>
		<title>John Wesley Honors College Awards 2014 Aldersgate Prize to Literature Scholar</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/jwhc-awards-2014-aldersgate-prize/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/jwhc-awards-2014-aldersgate-prize/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2014 15:34:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Honors College]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6408</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The John Wesley Honors College at Indiana Wesleyan University has the privilege each year of awarding the Aldersgate Prize. Motivated by the ethos of its liberal learning community, this book prize celebrates the outstanding achievement of an author whose scholarly inquiry challenges reductionist trends in academia by yielding a broad, integrative analysis of life’s complexities and shedding fresh light on ultimate questions that enliven Christian conceptions of human flourishing. Dr. Christina Bieber Lake, the Clyde S. Kilby Professor of English at Wheaton College, is the recipient of the 2014 Aldersgate Prize for her book, Prophets of the Posthuman: American Literature, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The <a href="http://www.indwes.edu/Academics/JWHC/" target="_blank">John Wesley Honors College</a> at Indiana Wesleyan University has the privilege each year of awarding the Aldersgate Prize. Motivated by the ethos of its liberal learning community, this book prize celebrates the outstanding achievement of an author whose scholarly inquiry challenges reductionist trends in academia by yielding a broad, integrative analysis of life’s complexities and shedding fresh light on ultimate questions that enliven Christian conceptions of human flourishing.</p>
<p><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/BieberLake-cont.jpg"><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/BieberLake-cont.jpg" alt="BieberLake-cont" width="140" height="170" class="alignright size-full wp-image-6415" /></a><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/BieberLake-cont-%281%29.jpg"></a><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/10/BieberLake-cont-%281%29.jpg"></a><a href="http://www.wheaton.edu/Academics/Faculty/B/Christina-Bieber-Lake" target="_blank">Dr. Christina Bieber Lake</a>, the Clyde S. Kilby Professor of English at Wheaton College, is the recipient of the 2014 Aldersgate Prize for her book, <em>Prophets of the Posthuman: American Literature, Biotechnology, and the Ethics of Personhood</em>.</p>
<p>After reviewing some seventy nominations for this year’s prize, the selection committee was most impressed with Bieber Lake’s wide-ranging and prophetic interrogation of the assumptions and aspirations that animate our biotechnological age. As one committee member put it, “By drawing deeply on the particular strengths of her discipline, Bieber Lake demonstrates compellingly that we can navigate the treacherous ethical terrain of biogenetic technology with greater confidence and acumen by becoming careful readers of certain influential authors of American fiction whose stories have already mapped out the topography of this terrain in vivid and thought-provoking detail.”</p>
<p>Bieber Lake will accept the Aldersgate Prize and its monetary award of $3,500 at the 2015 Celebration of Scholarship Luncheon (April 17, 2015) at Indiana Wesleyan University, where she will offer the keynote address.</p>
<p>Read more about this year&#8217;s Aldersgate Prize <a href="http://www.indwes.edu/News/2014/John-Wesley-Honors-College-awards-2014-Aldersgate-Prize-to-Literature-Scholar/" target="_blank">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/jwhc-awards-2014-aldersgate-prize/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Indiana Start-Ups Receive Paid Interns Through IWU and Lilly</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/indiana-start-ups-receive-paid-interns-through-iwu-and-lilly/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/indiana-start-ups-receive-paid-interns-through-iwu-and-lilly/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2014 12:30:16 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Business]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiana]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6394</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Sixteen start-up businesses and organizations across Indiana were recently awarded paid interns from Indiana Wesleyan University and funded by a Lilly Endowment grant. The participating interns are undergraduate sophomores, juniors or seniors of the residential campus of Indiana Wesleyan University in Marion, Indiana. Over 40 start-up employers expressed interest and/or applied for paid interns, and 16 start-ups were selected based primarily on their projected ability to provide meaningful work for interns and the potential for full-time hire past the internship period. Start-ups awarded paid interns for fall 2014 are: Bluebridge Digital, Blush Events, Inc., Cast a Bigger Net, Citiquest.com, LLC, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Sixteen start-up businesses and organizations across Indiana were recently awarded paid interns from Indiana Wesleyan University and funded by a Lilly Endowment grant. The participating interns are undergraduate sophomores, juniors or seniors of the residential campus of Indiana Wesleyan University in Marion, Indiana.</p>
<p>Over 40 start-up employers expressed interest and/or applied for paid interns, and 16 start-ups were selected based primarily on their projected ability to provide meaningful work for interns and the potential for full-time hire past the internship period.</p>
<p>Start-ups awarded paid interns for fall 2014 are: Bluebridge Digital, Blush Events, Inc., Cast a Bigger Net, Citiquest.com, LLC, Fleetwood Computers, LLC, Good News Ventures, Inc., Indy Eleven, Lark’s Song, LLC, LifeData, LLC, Peoplocity, ReEngage Consultants, Scientifically Speaking, LLC, Socially Seasoned, LLC, Sticknsleaves, The Abbey Coffee Co. and TOPHAT LTD.</p>
<p>The paid internship program is an initiative of the “Accelerate Indiana” Lilly Endowment grant recently awarded to IWU. The grant funds 20 interns per semester to work 10-15 hours per week for start-up employers five years or younger. Applications for paid interns for the spring semester will be available October 1 for IWU students and Indiana start-up employers.</p>
<p>Contact Tiffany Snyder at <a href="mailto:tiffany.snyder@indwes.edu">tiffany.snyder@indwes.edu</a> for more information or to apply.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/indiana-start-ups-receive-paid-interns-through-iwu-and-lilly/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>S. Truett Cathy: Why Not</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/s-truett-cathy-why-not/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/s-truett-cathy-why-not/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 20:32:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[IWU History]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6385</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[“It’s nice to be with you today. It’s nice to be anywhere when you are 90 years old.” That is how S. Truett Cathy began his acceptance speech when he was inducted into the Indiana Wesleyan University Society of World Changers three years ago. He had a knack for making people laugh, but he also had a way of making us think about things in ways we hadn’t before. Cathy’s recent passing at the age of 93 gives us reason to remember his life and to learn from how he lived. The founder and chief executive officer of Chick-fil-A, Cathy [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2011-World-Changers-S.-Truett-Cathy-23-e1410380515139.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6387" src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/2011-World-Changers-S.-Truett-Cathy-23-e1410380515139-231x300.jpg" alt="2011 World Changers (S. Truett Cathy) 23" width="231" height="300" /></a>“It’s nice to be with you today. It’s nice to be anywhere when you are 90 years old.” That is how S. Truett Cathy began his acceptance speech when he was inducted into the Indiana Wesleyan University Society of World Changers three years ago.</p>
<p>He had a knack for making people laugh, but he also had a way of making us think about things in ways we hadn’t before. Cathy’s recent passing at the age of 93 gives us reason to remember his life and to learn from how he lived.</p>
<p>The founder and chief executive officer of Chick-fil-A, Cathy started the business in 1946 when he and his brother opened a small diner in Atlanta, Georgia. The restaurant prospered and in 1967 Cathy opened the first Chick-fil-A restaurant.</p>
<p>Life was simple for Cathy saying, “If you make good choices, you will get good results. Bad choices, bad results.”</p>
<p>Cathy built his life and business on hard work, humility, and biblical principles. He was a member of the First Baptist Church in Jonesboro, Georgia, where he taught the same Sunday school class for more than 50 years.</p>
<p>All Chick-fil-A restaurants operate with a “Closed-on-Sunday” policy, without exception. Cathy believed that giving employees Sunday off as a day for family, worship, fellowship, or rest communicated how Chick-fil-A views spiritual life and how it feels about its people.</p>
<p>In his address to IWU students, Cathy urged everyone to think about their impact on others. “You must realize the impact we have on other people,” said Cathy. “Even though you are being prepared to change the world, make sure you take care of your next-door neighbor as well.”</p>
<p>Cathy always felt called to serve people. His WinShape Foundation, founded in 1984, grew from his desire to “shape winners” by helping young people succeed in life through scholarships and other youth-support programs.</p>
<p>Cathy was a dedicated husband, father, and grandfather. He was constantly striving to be the best he could be in every area of his life.</p>
<p>At the end of his speech, Cathy left us with a question—simple, yet profound.</p>
<p>“So the question is, to Truett Cathy as well as to each of you, why not be our best at all times. Why not? Why not? Why not?” – S. Truett Cathy</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/s-truett-cathy-why-not/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>What to Think About The U.S. News and World Report Rankings</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/what-to-think-about-the-us-news-rankings/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/what-to-think-about-the-us-news-rankings/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2014 15:17:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Higher Education]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6377</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Don Sprowl Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs The U.S. News and World Report annual ranking of colleges and universities is out. Once we satisfy our natural curiosity to see how we came out we are confronted with the deeper question of whether or not we should care about how we came out.  I will present highlights of the former and then muse a bit on the latter. This year we are tied for 26th place among Masters universities of the Midwest along with Grand Valley State, Webster, and the University of Indianapolis.  In addition, we are ranked number 7 on [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><em>Don Sprowl</em><br />
<em>Executive Vice President for Academic Affairs</em></p>
<p><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/MG_3218.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6382" src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/MG_3218-300x200.jpg" alt="_MG_3218" width="300" height="200" /></a>The U.S. News and World Report annual <span style="color: #800000;"><a href="http://colleges.usnews.rankingsandreviews.com/best-colleges/rankings" target="_blank"><span style="color: #800000;">ranking of colleges and universities is out</span></a></span>. Once we satisfy our natural curiosity to see how we came out we are confronted with the deeper question of whether or not we should care about how we came out.  I will present highlights of the former and then muse a bit on the latter.</p>
<p>This year we are <span style="color: #800000;"><a href="http://colleges.usnews.rankingsandreviews.com/best-colleges/rankings/regional-universities-midwest" target="_blank"><span style="color: #800000;">tied for 26<sup>th</sup></span></a> </span>place among Masters universities of the Midwest along with Grand Valley State, Webster, and the University of Indianapolis.  In addition, we are ranked number 7 on their “Great Schools, Great Prices” list, tied for 11th on their “Best Colleges for Veterans” list, and are included on their “A+ Schools for B Students” list.</p>
<p>Whether we should care about our placement in the U.S. News rankings depends on how well the U.S. News rankings formula matches our institutional values – what could be greater folly than abandoning our institutional identity and mission in pursuit of the approval of U.S. News and World Report.  The details of the U.S. News formula are proprietary, but the basic parameters are simple enough.  The U.S. News rankings favor resources, selectivity, and reputation.  Rich, highly-selective institutions that have a reputation for academic quality fare well.  Princeton and Harvard vie each year for the trophy in the National Universities category and schools like Williams, Amherst, Swarthmore, and Wellesley are perennially at the top of the National Liberal Arts Colleges group.  We wouldn’t mind being rich and we hope to build a reputation for academic quality, but we do not aspire to be highly selective.  Rather our mission has always driven us to open the doors of opportunity to every student to whom we might minister.  Thus, if we climb too high in the rankings it is probably a good indication that we have drifted from who we mean to be.</p>
<p>The Midwest Regional Universities category we are placed in, which includes about 150 schools, is led by ten or twelve schools that score notably higher than the rest.  The next twenty or so schools score close to each other so a small change in institutional numbers can produce a change in ranking.   In recent years we have climbed from the mid-30s to an all-time high of tied for 17th last year.  With little change in institutional character to point to, my guess is that external exposure through things like the National Conversations and the fruit of the Provost’s scholarship initiative that President Wright engineered a few years ago are slowly raising our exposure and reputation.  The drop to 26<sup>th</sup> this year is due largely to a correction in our reporting of admission rates.  If we attend well to our mission, this mid-teens to mid-20s place in the rankings feels about right.</p>
<p>The game of college rankings is changing in interesting ways.  U.S. News publishes their rankings for one reason – to sell magazines and college guide books.  Their success at making money in this way has not gone unnoticed and now every magazine and their grandmother are publishing college rankings.  The resulting glut of rankings, all using different methods and all producing different lists, has a muting effect on the impact of the rankings.  When U.S. News was the only game in town their rankings had an aura of authority and therefore validity.  With a multiplicity of conflicting rankings it is easier to realize that each ranking has meaning only in the context of what they value in their calculations.  Even in the context of the formulas, it is reasonable to ask whether a college ranking can have real meaning.  IWU, Grand Valley State, Webster, and the University of Indianapolis are all universities in the Midwest, but our missions and identities are profoundly different.  Is there really a way to ask which is the better school that would give a meaningful answer in an overall sense?  All of this muddling helps the rankings find their proper, minimal place in the landscape of higher education.</p>
<p>One day each year I am curious to see how U.S. News has placed us in their list.  The other 364 days I treasure the mission we have been given at IWU and pursue that without further thought that this year we are tied for 26<sup>th</sup>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/what-to-think-about-the-us-news-rankings/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IWU Hosts 25th Anniversary Colescott Golf Tournament</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-hosts-25th-anniversary-colescott-golf-tournament/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-hosts-25th-anniversary-colescott-golf-tournament/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 16:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6366</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University will host the 25th Jack and Marge Colescott Athletic Scholarship Golf Tournament on September 11 at Arbor Trace Golf Club in Marion. Colescott, inducted into the Indiana Basketball Hall of Fame in 1997 and the Grant County Sports Hall of Fame in 2009, served Grant County as a coach and athletic director for nearly 50 years. Jack went to Gas City High School, where he met his late wife, Marge. Through decades of coaching and raising their four children, she was always by his side—60 years of marriage.  Jack continues to honor her memory by giving back [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indiana Wesleyan University will host the 25<sup>th</sup> Jack and Marge Colescott Athletic Scholarship Golf Tournament on September 11 at Arbor Trace Golf Club in Marion.</p>
<p>Colescott, inducted into the <span style="color: #800000;"><a href="http://www.hoopshall.com/hall-of-fame/jack-colescott/?back=HallofFame" target="_blank"><span style="color: #800000;">Indiana Basketball Hall of Fame</span></a></span> in 1997 and the <span style="color: #800000;"><a href="http://grantcountysportshalloffame.org/inductee/jack-colescott/5" target="_blank"><span style="color: #800000;">Grant County Sports Hall of Fame</span></a></span> in 2009, served Grant County as a coach and athletic director for nearly 50 years.</p>
<p>Jack went to Gas City High School, where he met his late wife, Marge. Through decades of coaching and raising their four children, she was always by his side—60 years of marriage.  Jack continues to honor her memory by giving back to the community that they both loved so much.</p>
<p>The tournament awards scholarships to student-athletes from Grant County in addition to providing athletic scholarships for IWU students. The Jack and Marge Colescott Athletic Scholarship is a testament of a lifetime of service to Grant County and IWU.</p>
<p>&#8220;In addition to the huge impact that the Colescott event has made on our IWU student athletes through the athletic scholarship endowment it supports, the value of the event carrying the names of Jack and Marge Colescott goes way beyond monetary,” said IWU Athletic Director Mark DeMichael. “When people see the names of Jack and Marge Colescott, they think character, integrity, excellence and humility, all values that IWU Athletics strives for every day. It is an honor to have the Colescotts’ name on an event that is associated with Wildcat Athletics.&#8221;</p>
<p>For sponsorship opportunities or to register an individual or team, contact Lance Percy, associate vice president for University Relations at 765.677.2135 or email: <span style="color: #800000;"><a href="mailto:ur.events@indwes.edu"><span style="color: #800000;">ur.events@indwes.edu</span></a></span>.</p>
<p>Visit <span style="color: #800000;"><a href="http://www.indwes.edu/University-Relations/Jack-Colescott/Jack-Colescott/"><span style="color: #800000;">http://www.indwes.edu/University-Relations/Jack-Colescott/Jack-Colescott/</span></a></span> for more information or to register.</p>
<p>A Colescott celebration banquet is scheduled for September 10 in the IWU Barnes Student Center.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-hosts-25th-anniversary-colescott-golf-tournament/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IWU Names Dr. Jerry Pattengale as First University Professor</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-names-first-university-professor/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-names-first-university-professor/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 14:26:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Educational Leadership]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6361</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University, founded in 1920, has named Dr. Jerry Pattengale its first University Professor. The title of University Professor is conferred by the president, voted by faculty, and is reserved to “honor exceptional individuals whose scholarship and service transcend traditional disciplinary boundaries and are celebrated in the global academy.” “The breadth of his scholarly contributions is remarkable,” said Dr. Don Sprowl, Executive Vice President of Academic Affairs, “touching on topics from ancient history and Biblical antiquities to student success and Christian higher education.” In 2012 Pattengale received the IWU World Changing Faculty Award, only the second ever awarded. USC’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Jerry-Pattengale-8062-1.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6363" src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/09/Jerry-Pattengale-8062-1-300x240.jpg" alt="Jerry Pattengale - 8062-1" width="300" height="240" /></a>Indiana Wesleyan University, founded in 1920, has named Dr. Jerry Pattengale its first University Professor. The title of University Professor is conferred by the president, voted by faculty, and is reserved to “honor exceptional individuals whose scholarship and service transcend traditional disciplinary boundaries and are celebrated in the global academy.”</p>
<p>“The breadth of his scholarly contributions is remarkable,” said Dr. Don Sprowl, Executive Vice President of Academic Affairs, “touching on topics from ancient history and Biblical antiquities to student success and Christian higher education.”</p>
<p>In 2012 Pattengale received the IWU World Changing Faculty Award, only the second ever awarded. USC’s National Resource Center presented him the National Student Advocate Award in 2000, National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) a fellowship to Greece, and Azusa Pacific University two faculty-of-the-year awards. In addition to his books, filmed series and other scholarly work, he has published uplifting humor in <em>Buck Creek: True Stories to Tickle Your Mind</em>, selections from his newsprint series. His writings have also appeared in various leading venues, such as <em>Washington Post, Wall Street Journal, Christianity Today, InsideHigherEd, Books &amp; Culture</em> and <em>Chicago Tribune</em>, and he serves on the national board for the Religion News Service.</p>
<p>Sprowl said, “Always an encourager, Dr. Pattengale is a tireless supporter of the scholarly aspirations and work of students and colleagues, obtaining substantial external funding.”</p>
<p>Pattengale recently served as Assistant Provost for Public Engagement at IWU, leading the National Conversations through which IWU has gathered national and international leaders to engage the pressing public policy issues of our day. In Pattengale’s major current assignment he serves as Executive Director of the Green Scholars Initiative, an international collaboration of scholars to study the documents and artifacts of the Green Collection, the world’s largest private collection of rare biblical texts and artifacts, and he oversees an international curriculum project.</p>
<p>Pattengale also serves as Distinguished Senior Fellow in Baylor University’s Institute for Studies of Religion, Honorary Senior Research Associate with Tyndale House-Cambridge, Research Scholar with Gordon-Conwell Theological Seminary, Senior Fellow of the Sagamore Institute and Associate Publisher of <em>Christian Scholar’s Review.</em></p>
<p>“During my close collaboration with Dr Pattengale it has been a pleasure to see his devotion to education, care for students, wide knowledge, and outstanding organizational skills,” said Dr. Peter J. Williams, Warden and CEO, Tyndale House, Cambridge, UK. “As a leader of an institution dedicated to technical biblical research, I have also been quietly mentored by Dr Pattengale and have learned much from his godliness. It&#8217;s a delight therefore to see him receive the honour of being University Professor at IWU.”</p>
<p>Pattengale graduated from Marion College in 1979 and returned to Indiana Wesleyan University as a faculty member and administrator in 1997. He and his wife, Cindy, have four adult sons and reside in Marion, Indiana.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-names-first-university-professor/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IWU Honors Alex Huskey with Maidenberg Community Service Award</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-honors-alex-huskey-with-maidenberg-community-service-award/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-honors-alex-huskey-with-maidenberg-community-service-award/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 21:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Breaking News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6354</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Alex Huskey received the 2014 Tony Maidenberg Award for community service during Indiana Wesleyan University’s annual back-to-school convocation on August 20, 2014. President David Wright presented the award during the assembly of the IWU faculty and staff. Huskey has nearly 25 years of experience in law enforcement, first as a member of the Marion Police Department, and in recent years, as the superintendent of the Indiana Excise Police and the chairman of the Indiana Alcohol and Tobacco Commission. In addition, Huskey has also served as the pastor of New Bethany Church of God in Christ since 2007, and previously served [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/JN_5045.jpg"><img class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6358" src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/08/JN_5045-237x300.jpg" alt="_JN_5045" width="237" height="300" /></a>Alex Huskey received the 2014 Tony Maidenberg Award for community service during Indiana Wesleyan University’s annual back-to-school convocation on August 20, 2014. President David Wright presented the award during the assembly of the IWU faculty and staff.</p>
<p>Huskey has nearly 25 years of experience in law enforcement, first as a member of the Marion Police Department, and in recent years, as the superintendent of the Indiana Excise Police and the chairman of the Indiana Alcohol and Tobacco Commission.</p>
<p>In addition, Huskey has also served as the pastor of New Bethany Church of God in Christ since 2007, and previously served as the associate pastor of the church for 20 years.</p>
<p>“Each occupation is unique, but both represent the highest form of community service,” said President Wright. Next week, Huskey will begin a new form of community service as the President of the Marion campus of Ivy Tech community college.</p>
<p>Huskey has a bachelor’s degree in social and behavioral sciences, and a master’s degree in public policy and management from Indiana University. A veteran of the U.S. Air Force, he and his wife, Eileen, have two children.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-honors-alex-huskey-with-maidenberg-community-service-award/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IWU Formalizes Partnership with Australia Campus</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-formalizes-partnership-with-australia-campus/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-formalizes-partnership-with-australia-campus/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 14:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Breaking News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wesley Institute]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6345</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[President David Wright announces the partnership between IWU and Wesley Institute in Sydney, Australia, making their global Christian learning community a reality. Wesley Institute and IWU formalized on August 5, a partnership by which Wesley Institute seeks to become the foundation for the first global Christian university in Australia with plans to develop multiple campuses across the Asia Pacific region. Wesley Institute is a leading Christian college in Australia – celebrating over 30 years of operation in higher education. Indiana Wesleyan University has 94 years of experience in Christ-centred higher education. IWU enrolls 15,000 students in undergraduate and postgraduate degree [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>President David Wright announces the partnership between IWU and Wesley Institute in Sydney, Australia, making their global Christian learning community a reality. Wesley Institute and IWU formalized on August 5, a partnership by which Wesley Institute seeks to become the foundation for the first global Christian university in Australia with plans to develop multiple campuses across the Asia Pacific region.</p>
<p>Wesley Institute is a leading Christian college in Australia – celebrating over 30 years of operation in higher education. Indiana Wesleyan University has 94 years of experience in Christ-centred higher education. IWU enrolls 15,000 students in undergraduate and postgraduate degree courses, as well as innovative accelerated adult education and online delivery.</p>
<p>Combined, the two providers have the expertise to roll out Christian higher education across a broader range of undergraduate and postgraduate areas. In coming weeks, an application will be lodged with TEQSA for registration of Wesley Institute as a University College.  Subsequently the college plans to apply for registration as an Australian University.</p>
<p>Dr. Wright also announced that in, January 2015, Wesley Institute will change its name to Excelsia College.  Excelsia, ‘a community where people excel’, embodies the institution’s passion for the pursuit of academic, artistic and professional excellence within a Christian environment.</p>
<p>“With Christian schools being the fastest growing school sector in the country (Australia), there is an opportunity in the higher education market for students to continue holistic education in a Christian environment.  We intend to fulfill that need to assist students to realise their purpose,” said Wesley Institute Chief Executive, Dr Greg Rough.</p>
<p>Professor Bridget Aitchison, Vice Chancellor for Asia-Pacific, said, “With this partnership, we are able to expand Wesley Institute’s offerings across a range of discipline areas and degree levels.  We hope to create a truly global Christian learning community where faculty and students can benefit from collaborating with peers, exchanging knowledge and sharing resources.  We live in a globalized world and that is a reality we need to prepare our students to live and work in.”</p>
<p>It is anticipated that Wesley Institute will relocate to a new campus in 2015.  New courses could be offered as early as Semester 1, 2016.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/iwu-formalizes-partnership-with-australia-campus/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>#WesleyIsWaiting</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wesleyiswaiting/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wesleyiswaiting/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 01:53:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6335</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[While students enjoy their summer vacations, far away from IWU, Wesley Wildcat is waiting eagerly for his friends to come back and see him this fall. Less than a month left to go. Here&#8217;s what he&#8217;s been up to in the meantime:]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>While students enjoy their summer vacations, far away from IWU, Wesley Wildcat is waiting eagerly for his friends to come back and see him this fall.</p>
<p>Less than a month left to go.</p>
<p>Here&#8217;s what he&#8217;s been up to in the meantime:</p>
<p><iframe width="306" height="355" src="//instagram.com/p/qxJAvTqnCd/embed/" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="306" height="355" src="//instagram.com/p/rCQnpsKnB-/embed/" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="306" height="355" src="//instagram.com/p/rFnV5jKnPz/embed/" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="306" height="355" src="//instagram.com/p/q4ifM8KnJq/embed/" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="306" height="355" src="//instagram.com/p/q2Ju0mKnNV/embed/" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
<p><iframe width="306" height="355" src="//instagram.com/p/rAKMQFqnIb/embed/" frameborder="0" scrolling="no"></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wesleyiswaiting/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;The Perfect Fit&#8221;</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/the-perfect-fit/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/the-perfect-fit/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2014 01:40:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Athletics]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6333</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Troy Daily news has a story today about Grant Zawadzki, a IWU Wildcats basketball recruit who has spent the summer recovering from a knee injury: “Before I even found out how serious it was, they told me that they were still behind me,” he said. “They said they believed in me no matter what.” That’s how Zawadzki knew that not only did he want to go to Indiana Wesleyan, but the Wildcats wanted him there just as strongly. Troy Christian’s point guard, who will be entering his senior year when school begins, made his college decision over the summer, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The Troy Daily news <a href="http://tdn-net.com/news/localsports-sports/50125532/The-perfect-fit#.U9rT96JX-ub">has a story today </a>about Grant Zawadzki, a IWU Wildcats basketball recruit who has spent the summer recovering from a knee injury:</p>
<blockquote><p>“Before I even found out how serious it was, they told me that they were still behind me,” he said. “They said they believed in me no matter what.”</p>
<p>That’s how Zawadzki knew that not only did he want to go to Indiana Wesleyan, but the Wildcats wanted him there just as strongly.</p>
<p>Troy Christian’s point guard, who will be entering his senior year when school begins, made his college decision over the summer, choosing to play basketball for the Indiana Wesleyan University Wildcats — the defending national champions in NAIA Division II.</p>
<p>“It was just a perfect fit for me,” Zawadzki said. “They’re a national basketball powerhouse program, and the culture there was just something I couldn’t pass up. They fit my belief system perfectly. Not only will they make me a better student and basketball player, but also a better person.”</p>
<p>And that belief system is something that’s always been important to Zawadzki, as well as Troy Christian’s boys basketball program since his father Ray Zawadzki became head coach.</p>
<p>“They say that ‘you’re third.’ They tell you to put God first, other second and yourself third,” Zawadzki said. “It’s not about you. It’s about others and God. A program with that type of attitude is rare to find.</p></blockquote>
<p>Read the full story <a href="http://tdn-net.com/news/localsports-sports/50125532/The-perfect-fit#.U9rT96JX-ub">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/the-perfect-fit/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Serving Students at First Friday</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/serving-students-at-first-friday/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/serving-students-at-first-friday/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2014 06:17:04 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6324</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Once again this year, Indiana Wesleyan University is providing students in area schools with free bags of personal hygiene products during the August 1 First Friday Celebration in downtown Marion. These bags are designed to supplement the school supplies that several churches donate each year. Each bag contains a toothbrush, a tube of toothpaste, dental floss, soap and deodorant. &#8220;Faculty, staff and administrators worked for weeks to put these packets together,&#8221; said Roger Alcock, director of the Office of Events. &#8220;We really appreciate the chance to serve our hometown.&#8221; Students can pick up the bags at the IWU First Friday [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Toothbrush_x2_20050716_003.jpg"><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/Toothbrush_x2_20050716_003-300x224.jpg" alt="Toothbrush_x2_20050716_003" width="300" height="224" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6326" /></a>Once again this year, Indiana Wesleyan University is providing students in area schools with free bags of personal hygiene products during the <a href="https://www.facebook.com/events/1488611458021221/">August 1 First Friday Celebration</a> in downtown Marion.</p>
<p>These bags are designed to supplement the school supplies that several churches donate each year. Each bag contains a toothbrush, a tube of toothpaste, dental floss, soap and deodorant.</p>
<p>&#8220;Faculty, staff and administrators worked for weeks to put these packets together,&#8221; said Roger Alcock, director of the Office of Events. &#8220;We really appreciate the chance to serve our hometown.&#8221;</p>
<p>Students can pick up the bags at the IWU First Friday booth.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/serving-students-at-first-friday/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Teach a Few to Teach Millions</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/teach-a-few-to-teach-millions/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/teach-a-few-to-teach-millions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2014 14:40:06 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Educational Leadership]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6307</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Dr. Brad Oliver, associate professor of education for the IWU School of Educational Leadership, has been in the Democratic Republic of the Congo with a team sent to work on the Elephant Project, an initiative to train Christian primary and secondary school teachers in Congo on the proper way to integrate faith with education. He sent an email to President Wright on Sunday: Tonight, the team got the shock of its life. We looked up from eating in the hotel café and found ourselves on the national newscast. They did a feature story on the Elephant Project, showing footage from [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/11/Kinshasa_Congo-1024x685.jpg" align="right" width="374" height="250" style="padding-left: 10px; padding-bottom: 10px;" />Dr. Brad Oliver, associate professor of education for the IWU <a href="http://www.indwes.edu/academics/caps/school-of-educational-leadership/">School of Educational Leadership</a>, has been in the Democratic Republic of the Congo with a team sent to work on <a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/the-elephant-project/">the Elephant Project</a>, an initiative to train Christian primary and secondary school teachers in Congo on the proper way to integrate faith with education.</p>
<p>He sent an email to President Wright on Sunday:</p>
<blockquote><p>Tonight, the team got the shock of its life. We looked up from eating in the hotel café and found ourselves on the national newscast. They did a feature story on the Elephant Project, showing footage from the first week’s training sessions. Millions of Congolese in Kinshasa are now aware of the Elephant Project and the three-year-old partnership of IWU, Cairn, Cedarville, Southeastern Baptist Theological Seminary, and the Association of Christian Schools International in the DRC.</p>
<p>The national Education Coordinator, Papa Lala, has identified 95 of the best teachers throughout Congo. They are in Kinshasa for two weeks. The national church has taken unprecedented steps to house these educators while we equip them to go back to their national regions and start training school leaders and teachers in aspects of spiritual formation, pedagogy and leadership. Last week, the three spiritual formation modules were completed and the school leaders are discussing at length the need to make certain teachers are in a right relationship with God through faith in Jesus Christ. This week, I am lead-teaching on effective teaching and learning, while Debbie MacCullough trains them on classroom management and Mitogo Opira teaches the module on assessment.</p>
<p>&#8230;It is our hope their President will see the benefit of starting a teacher training program. As many of you are aware, the few Bible colleges which exist in DRC do not prepare teachers. The Elephant Project represents the first national undertaking to improve the quality of the 18,500 Protestant church schools that serve over 5.8 million children.</p></blockquote>
<p>To read more about the work of the School of Educational Leadership, <a href="http://www.indwes.edu/academics/caps/school-of-educational-leadership/">visit their page here</a>.</p>
<p><em>Photo: Wikipedia/Irene2005</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/teach-a-few-to-teach-millions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saving for a Rainy Day</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/saving-for-a-rainy-day/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/saving-for-a-rainy-day/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 01:06:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Life]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6300</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Indiana Public Media&#8217;s Noon Edition radio program has an interview with Timothy Bowman, director of the Ron Blue Institute for Financial Planning at Indiana Wesleyan University. Bowman offers financial advice for Indiana parents, most of whom lack &#8220;rainy day&#8221; accounts for emergencies. He says it’s important to see the big picture when making steep purchases because one financial decision effects what you can afford later on. “Do I want to have kids? Do we both want to work and focus on our careers?” he says. “As you start thinking about that, then you realize that the house that I buy, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Indiana Public Media&#8217;s Noon Edition radio program <a href="http://indianapublicmedia.org/noonedition/hoosiers-lack-rainy-day-accounts/">has an interview with Timothy Bowman</a>, director of the Ron Blue Institute for Financial Planning at Indiana Wesleyan University. Bowman offers financial advice for Indiana parents, most of whom lack &#8220;rainy day&#8221; accounts for emergencies.</p>
<blockquote><p>He says it’s important to see the big picture when making steep purchases because one financial decision effects what you can afford later on.</p>
<p>“Do I want to have kids? Do we both want to work and focus on our careers?” he says. “As you start thinking about that, then you realize that the house that I buy, that impacts what we can do some of our family things. The car that we buy, that has an impact. There’s no independent financial decision.”</p></blockquote>
<p>Read the <a href="http://indianapublicmedia.org/noonedition/hoosiers-lack-rainy-day-accounts/">full interview here</a>. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/saving-for-a-rainy-day/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Stellar Community</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/a-stellar-community/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/a-stellar-community/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2014 19:19:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Video]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6281</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[WIWU-TV has cooperated with the City of Marion to create a video putting the city&#8217;s heritage, community values and future development plans on display. As WIWU reported earlier this year, Marion is a 2014 finalist for the Indiana Stellar Communities program. Produced by Mark Fauser, City of Marion and Randall E. King, WIWU-TV.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>WIWU-TV has cooperated with the City of Marion to create a video putting the city&#8217;s heritage, community values and future development plans on display.</p>
<p>As WIWU <a href="http://www.wiwutv.com/making-marion-stellar/">reported earlier this year</a>, Marion is a 2014 finalist for the Indiana <a href="http://www.in.gov/ocra/2601.htm">Stellar Communities</a> program.</p>
<p><iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/6lWjCOmqhJ8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p>Produced by Mark Fauser, City of Marion and Randall E. King, WIWU-TV.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/a-stellar-community/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Loving the LGBTQ Communities</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/loving-the-lgbtq-communities/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/loving-the-lgbtq-communities/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2014 19:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Outreach]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6268</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[IWU student Phil Ross has a post today on Love is an Orientation, a blog from the Chicago-based Marin Foundation, a Christian ministry that shares the love of Jesus Christ with LGBTQ individuals in Chicago and elsewhere. Ross is serving a summer internship with the Marin Foundation. In the post, Ross tells the story of his own life, of having grown up being bullied by people who thought he was gay and of how God used that experience to give him a special empathy for people in the LGBTQ communities: As I learn to embrace my own identity and God’s unconditional love [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>IWU student Phil Ross <a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/loveisanorientation/2014/07/philross/">has a post today</a> on Love is an Orientation, a blog from the Chicago-based <a href="http://www.themarinfoundation.org">Marin Foundation</a>, a Christian ministry that shares the love of Jesus Christ with LGBTQ individuals in Chicago and elsewhere. Ross is serving a summer internship with the Marin Foundation.</p>
<p>In the post, Ross tells the story of his own life, of having grown up being bullied by people who thought he was gay and of how God used that experience to give him a special empathy for people in the LGBTQ communities:</p>
<blockquote><p><em>As I learn to embrace my own identity and God’s unconditional love for me, I’ve become increasingly aware of his unconditional love <strong>for all people </strong>– regardless of race, gender, gender identity, orientation, ethnicity, socio-economic status…and the list goes on.</em></p>
<p><em>Wherever we go and whatever we do, we know we have a resting place in our Lord. As I grow in understanding of what it is to live in true and proper worship of God, I take comfort that my same God promises us safety.</em></p>
<p><em>“The Lord is my shepherd, I lack nothing. He makes me lie down in green pastures, he leads me beside quiet waters, he refreshes my soul. He guides me along the right paths for his name’s sake. Even though I walk through the darkest valley, I will fear no evil, for you are with me; your rod and your staff, they comfort me” (Psalm 23:1-4).</em></p></blockquote>
<p>Read <a href="http://www.patheos.com/blogs/loveisanorientation/2014/07/philross/">the full blog post on Patheos</a>.</p>
<p><em>Photo credit: <a href="http://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/User:Onanymous">Onanymous</a></em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/loving-the-lgbtq-communities/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Say Hello To Noelle</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/say-hello-to-noelle/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/say-hello-to-noelle/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 19:53:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Nursing]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6262</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Say hello to Noelle. She doesn’t say much, but she’s an important new member of the School of Nursing (SON) family. The SON recently purchased a brand-new, high-tech Noelle-brand birthing  manikin for the Patient Care Simulation Lab. This high-fidelity manikin,  manufactured by the Gaumard Scientific Company, is an advanced birthing simulator that “delivers” a baby&#8211;the realistic, advanced-functioning newborn manikin, Hal. Noelle is designed to provide a complete birthing experience before, during and after delivery. The Noelle manikin is equipped with a precision programmable fetal delivery system for repeatable teaching exercises including normal, rapid and prolonged labor, and delivery simulations. Labor can be paused, continued  or accelerated at any time. The manikin [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_6263" style="width: 310px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/noelle.png"><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/07/noelle-300x282.png" alt="noelle" width="300" height="282" class="size-medium wp-image-6263" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Noelle and her continually-newborn son, Hal.</p></div>
<p>Say hello to Noelle. She doesn’t say much, but she’s an important new member of the School of Nursing (SON) family.</p>
<p>The SON recently purchased a brand-new, high-tech Noelle-brand birthing  manikin for the Patient Care Simulation Lab. This high-fidelity manikin,  manufactured by the Gaumard Scientific Company, is an advanced birthing simulator that “delivers” a baby&#8211;the realistic, advanced-functioning newborn manikin, Hal. Noelle is designed to provide a complete birthing experience before, during and after delivery.</p>
<p>The Noelle manikin is equipped with a precision programmable fetal delivery system for repeatable teaching exercises including normal, rapid and prolonged labor, and delivery simulations. Labor can be paused, continued  or accelerated at any time. The manikin can be programmed so that each student receives exactly the same scenario, but it also includes 30 obstetric scenarios that can be modified as the instructor requires. Scenarios and their results can be saved and shared for later use.</p>
<p>Maternal/newborn Assistant Professor Angela Bailey, MSN, RN noted that, among other benefits, “our Noelle manikin has afforded us the opportunity for a more realistic post-partum hemorrhage in-class simulation, which has significantly improved pre- to post-test quiz scores.”</p>
<p>Noelle is widely considered to be the leading high-fidelity birthing manikin.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/say-hello-to-noelle/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>“All I know is how to be a chaplain”</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/all-i-know-is-how-to-be-a-chaplain/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/all-i-know-is-how-to-be-a-chaplain/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2014 02:22:23 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Friends of IWU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6255</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Richard Bareiss can be forgiven if he doesn’t respond immediately when someone calls him by his first  name. For the past 60 years, Bareiss has answered not to the name, Richard, but to the title, Chaplain. After graduating from Houghton College and Gordon Theological Seminary, Bareiss was commissioned as a chaplain in the U.S. Navy in 1954. After retiring from the Navy, he became the first chaplain at Houghton and later served as the first chaplain at Indiana Wesleyan University. His 20 years in the Navy was matched by his 20 years as a chaplain at the two colleges: nine [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Screenshot-2014-06-26-at-10.12.06-PM-269x300.png" alt="Screenshot 2014-06-26 at 10.12.06 PM" width="269" height="300" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6257" />Richard Bareiss can be forgiven if he doesn’t respond immediately when someone calls him by his first  name. For the past 60 years, Bareiss has answered not to the name, Richard, but to the title, Chaplain.</p>
<div>After graduating from Houghton College and Gordon Theological Seminary, Bareiss was commissioned as a chaplain in the U.S. Navy in 1954. After retiring from the Navy, he became the first chaplain at Houghton and later served as the first chaplain at Indiana Wesleyan University.</div>
<div>
<div></div>
<div>His 20 years in the Navy was matched by his 20 years as a chaplain at the two colleges: nine years at Houghton and 11 years at IWU.</div>
<div></div>
<div>After retiring at IWU, Bariess was instrumental in establishing chaplaincy programs for both the Marion Police Department and the Grant County Sheriff’s Department.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“All I know is how to be a chaplain,” said Bareiss, who now lives with his wife, Elinore, in an apartment at Colonial Oaks, an IWU-owned retirement community near the Marion campus.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Elinore Bareiss shares a story of Richard’s first year at IWU, where their daughter, Cathy, also was a student.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“Cathy was walking across campus one day, a few steps behind her father,” Elinore said.  “She called out a couple times, ‘Dad! Dad!’ When he did not respond Cathy tried another approach, ‘Chaplain!’ That caught her father’s attention.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>It came as little surprise in 2012 when Richard and Elinore Bareiss decided to establish the Military Chaplain’s Endowed Scholarship Fund at IWU. One criterion for the renewable scholarship is that recipients must be dependents of Wesleyan military chaplains, either active duty or retired.</div>
<div></div>
<div>In addition to giving $1,000 annually to fund the scholarship, the Bareisses also have included IWU in their will and have established an annuity.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Richard and Elinore Bareiss met as students at Houghton College, a Wesleyan sister institution of IWU in upstate New York. Richard was a native of Massachusetts, and Elinore came from Long Island, New York.</div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>
<div>“I went to a Baptist church when I was a child but never heard the gospel,” Richard said. “When I told my high school pastor that I was going to Houghton, he said, “ ‘Don’t let those Wesleyans mess up your theology.’ ”</div>
<div></div>
<div>“I was endorsed by the Baptist church during my career in the Navy, but denominational titles don’t mean much in the military because you minister to people from all backgrounds,” he said.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Elinore was raised in a conservative Baptist church on Long Island. “They were not too happy when I went to Houghton,” she said.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Richard and Elinore were married in 1952 after they graduated from Houghton, and will celebrate their 62nd wedding anniversary in June.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Their current apartment in Marion is their 17th home since they were married. They have four children.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The Bariesses spent their first two years of married life in Massachusetts as Richard completed work on his Master of Divinity</div>
<div>degree at the Gordon Seminary. While he was on active duty, Richard earned two additional master’s degrees, one in counseling and the other in student development services.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Elinore Bareiss earned a bachelor’s degree from Houghton with a major in Christian education and minors in Bible and psychology.</div>
<div></div>
</div>
<div>
<div>For many of his 20 years in the Navy, Richard’s primary residence was aboard a ship while Elinore was at home with their children. At various times, the family lived on the East Coast, the West Coast and in Hawaii.</div>
<div></div>
<div>One of Richard’s more interesting experiences in the Navy was his assignment as the chaplain for an entire squadron of eight destroyers. He explained: “They moved me from ship to ship with something called a high line. They did that by positioning two ships parallel within about 20 yards of each other and then throwing a line from one ship to the other. Then they put me in a chair attached to the line and pulled me from ship to ship.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“One day, I was transferred eight times. It was better than a $2 ride at an amusement park. Today they do it with helicopters,” Bareiss said.</div>
<div></div>
<div>The U.S. Navy also provides chaplains for the Marines and the Coast Guard, and Bareiss was called on at various times to serve both those branches of the military.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“One of my last deployments, for nine months, was as a Marine chaplain in Vietnam,” he said. “That is where the bad guys had my name on an assassination list. I guess they didn’t like me.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>His last tour of duty was with the Coast Guard.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“I never intended that I would spend my entire 40-year career in ministry as a chaplain instead of being a traditional pastor of a church,” Richard Bareiss said.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“That is just the way the Lord led us,” Elinore Bareiss said.</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/all-i-know-is-how-to-be-a-chaplain/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Irrepressible Joy</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/irrepressible-joy/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/irrepressible-joy/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2014 18:35:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Alumni]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[slider]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6247</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Chelsea Rethlake died of cancer on September 29, 2013, one year after graduating with a degree in math education. Well into 2014, her Facebook wall remains current with notes and updates from her friends: April 1: Britta Sjoberg: “I heard ‘Man in the Mirror’ playing in the store today and I thought of the time you, Kelsey and I were rocking out to MJ on our way to a corn maze in Kokomo. But for real, when were you not jamming to MJ&#8217;s tunes? “I miss your enthusiasm and love of life. You left an amazing legacy.” March 11: Hailey [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Screenshot-2014-06-16-at-2.29.05-PM.png"><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Screenshot-2014-06-16-at-2.29.05-PM.png" alt="Screenshot 2014-06-16 at 2.29.05 PM" width="220" height="213" class="alignright size-full wp-image-6249" /></a>Chelsea Rethlake died of cancer on September 29, 2013, one year after graduating with a degree in math education.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Well into 2014, her Facebook wall remains current with notes and updates from her friends:</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>April 1: Britta Sjoberg:</strong> “I heard ‘Man in the Mirror’ playing in the store today and I thought of the time you, Kelsey and I were rocking out to MJ on our way to a corn maze in Kokomo. But for real, when were you not jamming to MJ&#8217;s tunes?</div>
<div></div>
<div>“I miss your enthusiasm and love of life. You left an amazing legacy.”</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>March 11: Hailey Ann Tompkins:</strong> “Hey Chelsea Morgan. Today was a rough one. I miss you. Most times, I still don&#8217;t believe it. I love you. As always, wish you were here.”</div>
<div></div>
<div><strong>February 2: Amanda Smith:</strong> “We miss you at The River Chelsea, but we know you are enjoying a happiness none of us could even imagine right now.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>People close to Chelsea consistently remember a person full of joy. Her smile, her laughter and her words of encouragement for those she cared about are what people hold onto when they think about who she was.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“There was no hiding Chelsea’s joy of her salvation,” said Pastor Matt Trexler ‘99 of The River Community Church in Marion, where Chelsea attended since its founding in 2007. “She had this amazing ability to brighten a room with who Christ was in her.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>When she found out about the cancer, Trexler recalls, her thoughts were for other people before herself.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“Chelsea’s prayer simply was, even in that first conversation, ‘Matthew, I’ll do cancer if somehow my family can come to know Jesus’&#8230;Chelsea never got to see the completion of that on this side of heaven.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>
<div>She never lost faith,” says her mother, Pam Zirzow. “You never heard her complain&#8230; she continued working and going to school and all of her church activities, all through her chemo and radiation.”</div>
<div></div>
<div><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Screenshot-2014-06-16-at-2.31.59-PM.png"><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/Screenshot-2014-06-16-at-2.31.59-PM-300x296.png" alt="Screenshot 2014-06-16 at 2.31.59 PM" width="210" height="207" class=" wp-image-6250 alignleft" /></a>Three weeks before Chelsea passed away, her mother gave her life to Christ.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“She had just been told on a Thursday that we were out of time, we were out of treatments, and that she probably had two to five weeks left. She asked me if I’d take her to church, and I did, and she walked in and started singing and raising her hands in praise, and I was just amazed….the joy on her face, and the peace in her face, there had to be something to it.”</div>
<div></div>
<div>At the celebration of life event that The River held to honor Chelsea, her mother was baptized in a portable tank brought in for the event. Spontaneously, several other people chose to be baptized as well, including Chelsea’s uncle and his family.</div>
<div></div>
<div>Chelsea’s story, as told by her friends and through her blog, has influenced people across Marion and even throughout the world to make decisions for Christ.</div>
<div></div>
<div>“Chelsea’s prayer was answered,” Trexler said. “Her cancer and her death were not in vain. Chelsea walked with cancer&#8230;with a faith and with a joy that I’ve never seen before.”</div>
</div>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/irrepressible-joy/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Young Adults Who Love Church, Part 3: Sharing God&#8217;s Story</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/young-adults-who-love-church-part-3-sharing-gods-story/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/young-adults-who-love-church-part-3-sharing-gods-story/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2014 13:07:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Alumni]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6243</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[What Gabe Melian and the other core members of Overflow have found in their year of ministry in Florida is that many Millennials won’t be receptive to your message until you’ve earned their trust as a person. “We want to share God’s story through everyday life,” Melian says. “We don’t want to see church as just a Sunday event as much as we want to see church and faith permeate every aspect of their lives.” A lot of time goes into correcting negative stereotypes of Christians that have arisen in recent years. “People have ideas of what church is like, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/melian.png"><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/melian-300x229.png" alt="melian" width="300" height="229" class="alignright size-medium wp-image-6244" /></a>What Gabe Melian and the other core members of Overflow have found in their year of ministry in Florida is that many Millennials won’t be receptive to your message until you’ve earned their trust as a person.</p>
<p>“We want to share God’s story through everyday life,” Melian says. “We don’t want to see church as just a Sunday event as much as we want to see church and faith permeate every aspect of their lives.”</p>
<p>A lot of time goes into correcting negative stereotypes of Christians that have arisen in recent years.</p>
<p>“People have ideas of what church is like, especially young adults, and a lot of times it’s negative because of these perceptions. But when they meet a Christian, when they meet a group of people that call themselves Christ-followers and just accept people and love them and spend time with them regardless of what they believe or whether they’re going to end up coming to your church or not, they really open up and you begin to change their perception of the church.”</p>
<p>For Overflow, social events and friendships have been the greatest tool to breaking down these prejudices.</p>
<p>“We’ve seen that a lot. We’ve seen atheists, we’ve seen gay people, we’ve seen people from other faiths, Buddhists, that are just like, ‘man, I used to have this perception of Christians and the church but since I’ve met you guys, I’ve just been way more open to considering some of the things that you guys talk about.’</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/young-adults-who-love-church-part-3-sharing-gods-story/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Young Adults Who Love Church, Part 3: The Hip-Hop Church</title>
		<link>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/young-adults-who-love-church-part-3-the-hip-hop-church/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/young-adults-who-love-church-part-3-the-hip-hop-church/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2014 12:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Alumni]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwuspectrum.com/?p=6238</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s rare that you’ll find a Wesleyan congregation that bills itself as “a hip-hop church.” “Everything from our worship, the way things look, to everything about it embodies the hip-hop culture,” says Pastor Troy Evans of The Edge Urban Fellowship. They meet in a century-old church building with stained glass windows and graffiti art in the lobby and sanctuary. “It’s a unique clash of traditional and modern and hip-hop.” While the service puts a unique spin on the worship experience, “It’s the other six days of the week that we are actually being family and church,” Evans says. The Edge [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/theedge.png"><img src="http://www.iwuspectrum.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/06/theedge-300x220.png" alt="theedge" width="300" height="220" class="alignleft size-medium wp-image-6239" /></a>It’s rare that you’ll find a Wesleyan congregation that bills itself as “a hip-hop church.”</p>
<p>“Everything from our worship, the way things look, to everything about it embodies the hip-hop culture,” says Pastor Troy Evans of The Edge Urban Fellowship. They meet in a century-old church building with stained glass windows and graffiti art in the lobby and sanctuary. “It’s a unique clash of traditional and modern and hip-hop.”</p>
<p>While the service puts a unique spin on the worship experience, “It’s the other six days of the week that we are actually being family and church,” Evans says.</p>
<p>The Edge has invested in church and community leaders by starting seven businesses in the past few years to help realize the ideas of entrepreneurial church members, each one with a ministry aspect.</p>
<p>“We believe strongly in building the people. What’s your mission, your vision, and how does your mission and vision tie in with what we do at The Edge?”</p>
<p>These businesses include a dance team, Momentum, which performed at IWU in February; a music studio in the basement;<br />
and a video production company.</p>
<p>“We have a young girl that’s 11 years old, she started her own accessory company. She does hair bows, and wallets, and all kinds of stuff like that,” Evans says.</p>
<p>This is The Edge’s way of creating leaders for the future.</p>
<p>“For us, it’s most important that we build into those leaders and then build their capacity so that they will be available for ministry for the long haul,” he says.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwuspectrum.com/young-adults-who-love-church-part-3-the-hip-hop-church/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
