<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Sojourn</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com</link>
	<description>Campus News for Indiana Wesleyan University</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 03:44:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.0.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Murray’s energy off of bench encourages men’s basketball</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstarsmurray/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstarsmurray/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 03:26:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Johnson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Front Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Aaron Murray]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greg Tonagel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IWU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Basketball]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=9026</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Aaron Murray (jr) had only played basketball for three years when he joined Indiana Wesleyan University’s men’s basketball team in 2012. Murray, a 6’10” center, was a missionary kid in Zambia, Africa from the age of 14 to 18, and first started playing basketball when he was 16 years old. That summer, his family was [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_9028" style="width: 223px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><img class="size-large wp-image-9028" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/Mens-Basketball-2014-716-213x320.jpg" alt="Murray is  (Courtesy Photo)" width="213" height="320" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Murray is still relatively new to the game of basketball. (Courtesy Photo)</p></div>
<p>Aaron Murray (jr) had only played basketball for three years when he joined Indiana Wesleyan University’s men’s basketball team in 2012.</p>
<p>Murray, a 6’10” center, was a missionary kid in Zambia, Africa from the age of 14 to 18, and first started playing basketball when he was 16 years old. That summer, his family was visiting their home church in Indianapolis, which had a Christian school affiliated with it.</p>
<p>The school had a basketball camp, and Murray decided to sign up for it. He realized he really enjoyed the game, and went back to play for a team in Zambia.</p>
<p>“We practiced twice a week for an hour and a half and all we had was two tournaments the entire season,” Murray said. “It wasn’t anything like basketball in the states.”</p>
<p>Murray continued to develop an interest in basketball, and he when he and his family moved to Louisville, Ky. for his senior year of high school, he played on his high school team there. As Murray’s senior year came to a close, he decided he wanted to play basketball in college.</p>
<p>But he wasn’t planning to attend IWU.</p>
<p>“I decided I wanted to go to one college, that I’ll leave nameless, and I figured out what I was going to study, talked to the coach, everything like that, and I was turning down all the other [schools],” Murray said.</p>
<p>Over the summer following his high school graduation, Murray went on a short-term missions trip to the Dominican Republic. There, he met Will Partin, a missionary who used to be an assistant basketball coach at IWU. Murray said Partin tried to convince him to attend IWU and join the basketball program.</p>
<p>“He said, ‘Indiana Wesleyan would be a perfect fit for you. They have great basketball, awesome learning.’ I had heard the spiel from all the Christian schools before,” Murray said. “But he said, ‘No, you really need to go here. At least let Coach [Tonagel] call you when you get back to the States.’”</p>
<p>Tonagel said Partin contacted him right away.</p>
<p>“He called us and said, ‘Hey, we have this kid from Louisville, he’s still looking for a school, he’s 6’10”, a hard worker, unselfish kid, I think he kind of fits what you are looking for,’” Tonagel said.</p>
<p>Tonagel then called Murray and invited him to come to an open gym at IWU on a Sunday over the summer to play with the basketball team, which was there helping with basketball camps. Murray accepted.</p>
<div id="attachment_9027" style="width: 436px" class="wp-caption alignright"><img class="wp-image-9027 size-large" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/DSCN1868-426x320.jpg" alt="Will Partin (left), a missionary in the Dominican Republic and former IWU men's basketball assistant coach, helped lead Murray (right) to IWU. (Courtesy Photo)" width="426" height="320" /><p class="wp-caption-text">Will Partin (left), a missionary in the Dominican Republic and former IWU men&#8217;s basketball assistant coach, helped lead Murray to IWU. (Courtesy Photo)</p></div>
<p>The men’s basketball coaching staff liked what it saw from Murray at the open gym, and offered him a spot on the team.</p>
<p>“Coach Tonagel said, ‘I won’t promise you a starting spot, I won’t promise you playing time, but if you come up here and work hard, I’ll promise you an opportunity,’” Murray said.</p>
<p>At that point, Murray was sold. He changed his mind and decided to attend IWU.</p>
<p>But when Murray joined the team during his freshman year, he wasn’t ready for the college game. He elected to redshirt his freshman year to hone his skills some more.</p>
<p>“I wasn’t very good, and you can say that [in your article], too,” Murray said. “I wasn’t very good and I had only been playing basketball for three years and just wanted an opportunity to grow and learn and get better at the fundamentals before wasting a year.”</p>
<p>And grow he did, according to Tonagel.</p>
<p>“[During that year], he got stronger, which was probably the most important thing, but he began to learn the game,” Tonagel said.</p>
<p>Murray’s game has continued to develop, and now, in his second year on the active roster, he is starting to earn more playing time for the defending NAIA Division II National Champion Wildcats.</p>
<p>But what Murray provides behind the scenes is what makes him so valuable to the team.</p>
<p>Murray said he relishes his role as someone who makes his teammates better through hard work in practice.</p>
<p>“I push the other big guys in practice everyday, like Lane [Mahurin], Josh [Mawhorr] and Nate [Bubash], because I know it makes the team better,” Murray said.</p>
<p>Tonagel also appreciates Murray’s unselfish attitude and the energy he provides from the bench during games.</p>
<p>“[He has] the ability to see the bigger picture, to care more about your teammates than yourself,” Tonagel said. “Aaron will be the first one off the bench when someone makes a good play. He loves to celebrate the success of others, and that’s a hallmark of an unselfish athlete.”</p>
<p>As a sports ministry major, Murray also aims to lead spiritually for the Wildcats. Murray said he aims to fill a part of the void Garvin Haughey (alumnus ’14) left when he graduated.</p>
<p>“When Garvin left, he left a huge, huge hole on our team that will never be filled the same way,” Murray said. “He was for sure the spiritual leader of the team, and I’ve tried to step into that role a little bit.”</p>
<p>Like most athletes, Murray would love to play lots of minutes, but the most important thing for him is contributing positively to a winning team.</p>
<p>“There’s the competitor in me that wants more playing time, and I’m striving for that every day by competing in practice,” Murray said. “But I don’t let my desire for playing time get in the way of my desire to see the team succeed.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><em>This story is a part of Co-Editor-in-Chief Jared Johnson&#8217;s &#8220;Stars in the Background&#8221; series on overlooked stars in IWU athletics. For more information, click <a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstars/">here</a>.</em></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstarsmurray/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stars in the Background: A Senior Project by Jared Johnson</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstars/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstars/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2014 02:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Johnson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Front Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports Columns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IWU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jared Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[stars in the background]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=9018</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[If someone asked you to name the first athlete that popped into your head, which athlete would you name? Would it be a star professional athlete known for amazing athletic abilities, like LeBron James or Peyton Manning? Or would it be an athlete, professional or otherwise, who is known mostly for positive character qualities? Chances [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p class="p1"><span class="s1"><img class="alignright size-full wp-image-9019" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/12/1dc4730.jpg" alt="1dc4730" width="200" height="200" />If someone asked you to name the first athlete that popped into your head, which athlete would you name? Would it be a star professional athlete known for amazing athletic abilities, like LeBron James or Peyton Manning? Or would it be an athlete, professional or otherwise, who is known mostly for positive character qualities? </span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Chances are, you would have picked one of the latter.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Nowadays, sports media focus most of their attention on the type of athlete who scores 20 points per game on the basketball court or passes for 300 yards per game on the gridiron. But what about the type of player who inspires his or her teammates in practice through hard work and competitiveness? How about those who have the gift of encouragement and use it to build their teammates up? Those types of athletes are often forgotten by media, as well as the general public.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I’m Jared Johnson, Co-Editor-in-Chief of The Sojourn, and for my senior project in the convergent journalism major, I wanted to do something about this bias in sports coverage.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I partnered with the Indiana Wesleyan University Athletic Department to write feature stories about nine IWU athletes. These Wildcats are all skilled in their sport, but a majority of their impact actually comes in ways other than their athletic talents, through a variety of ways. Each athlete was recommended by their coach, and I titled my project “Stars in the Background.”</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Since we are still in the fall season, I wrote a story about one athlete from each of IWU’s fall semester athletic teams. These teams are:</span></p>
<p class="p1"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstarsdaniello/"><span class="s1">Women’s tennis</span></a></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Men’s tennis</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Women’s golf</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Men’s golf</span></p>
<p class="p1"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstarsportera/"><span class="s1">Volleyball</span></a></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Women’s soccer</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Men’s soccer</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Women’s basketball</span></p>
<p class="p1"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstarsmurray/"><span class="s1">Men’s basketball </span></a></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I excluded men’s and women’s cross country, because I myself am a member of the men’s cross country team, and would not have the unbiased perspective needed to write those articles.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">Two of these articles, about athletes from IWU&#8217;s <a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstarsdaniello/">women’s tennis</a> and <a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstarsportera/">volleyball</a> teams, were posted on The Sojourn&#8217;s website and in print issues earlier in the semester.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">The remaining seven articles will be revealed one-by-one each day through the upcoming week, from Dec. 1 to Dec. 7. Each story will be linked on The Sojourn’s Facebook page as well as The Sojourn Sports’ Twitter page.</span></p>
<p class="p1"><span class="s1">I hope you enjoy reading about IWU’s “Stars in the Background.&#8221;</span></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/backgroundstars/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>How does social media use affect IWU students?</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/how-does-social-media-use-affect-iwu-students/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/how-does-social-media-use-affect-iwu-students/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2014 15:31:26 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kayla Thomas]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On Campus]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=9014</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Social media sites like Twitter, Facebook, Yik Yak, Tinder, Tumblr and Instagram are widely used throughout campus. While there are benefits to using social media, the tendency for students to post questionable content can cause more harm than good. These media offer some great benefits, such as the ability to stay in contact with our [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Social media sites like Twitter, Facebook, Yik Yak, Tinder, Tumblr and Instagram are widely used throughout campus. While there are benefits to using social media, the tendency for students to post questionable content can cause more harm than good.</p>
<p>These media offer some great benefits, such as the ability to stay in contact with our loved ones and receive news from around the world.</p>
<p>However, with the benefits there are downsides. Advancements in internet technology have given rise to major problems such as cyberbullying, online predators and the display of inappropriate behavior.</p>
<p>Many students are unclear on the university’s role in their social media, if the university can see and regulate it, and if they have the ability to take down anything they deem as unfit.</p>
<p>“If it violates a university policy, then the university can address an issue with the student,” Andrew Parker, vice president of student development, said. “The outcome of that pursuit could involve a simple conversation, or it could involve the student conduct process.”</p>
<p>In regards to the Internet and social media, the IWU handbook states:</p>
<p>“The internet has provided many advances and opportunities for students to connect in cyber-communities, not only on the IWU campus but also nationwide and globally. Students must be careful that the material that is posted on their accounts falls within University expectations. In addition, students need to be aware that the material on their site is open to public viewing … IWU monitors and filters all internet activity [on any computer hardware owned by IWU] and provides regular reports of internet use to the office of the Vice President for Student Development.”</p>
<p>With this in mind, while the university may not be hunting for social media posts that violate the handbook rules, they are capable of working with social media sites directly to remove inappropriate content.</p>
<p>IWU prefers to take a hands-off approach to social media, only getting involved when necessary.“The university attempts to use sound judgment in deciding which situations to address,” Parker says.</p>
<p>While social media keeps people connected, they can also create problems. For example, negative posts are frequently posted to Yik Yak regarding various topics including chapel and Baldwin. The tendency is to forget that even though posts written on social media are not directly spoken to the person, they still hold weight and have consequences.</p>
<p>“The negative impacts of social media are not unique to IWU&#8217;s campus. With so many different ways of sharing and viewing content, social media has a way of consuming us. It makes it harder for us to live in the moment,” Digital Media Manager Jay Filson said.</p>
<p>Social media is also affecting incoming students in a different way. IWU does not directly seek out incoming students’ social media accounts but do actively use social media as a way to connect and inform incoming students.</p>
<p>“We aim to meet students where they’re at. If they prefer to communicate with a counselor via a social media channel, we attempt to be present, reachable and interact with them in that medium,” Adam Farmer, Director of Admissions says. “Outside of this experience, we encounter a student’s social media profile rarely.”</p>
<p>IWU would like students to use social media with caution and remember that what people say can and does have an impact on others.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/how-does-social-media-use-affect-iwu-students/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IWU Alumni write on their wrestles with faith in a new compilation book</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/iwu-alumni-write-on-their-wrestles-with-faith-in-a-new-compilation-book/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/iwu-alumni-write-on-their-wrestles-with-faith-in-a-new-compilation-book/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2014 14:11:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brooke Eber]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IWU]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kissing in the Chapel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lauren Sawyer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Praying in the Frat House: Wrestling with Faith in College]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Steven Porter]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=9012</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Recent Indiana Wesleyan University graduates Lauren Sawyer (alumna ‘12) and Steven Porter (alumnus ‘12) are soon to be published in a new book. Entitled “Kissing in the Chapel, Praying in the Frat House: Wrestling with Faith in College,” the book is a compilation of essays written by recent college graduates about their personal experiences. “The [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recent Indiana Wesleyan University graduates Lauren Sawyer (alumna ‘12) and Steven Porter (alumnus ‘12) are soon to be published in a new book. Entitled “Kissing in the Chapel, Praying in the Frat House: Wrestling with Faith in College,” the <a href="http://www.adamjcopeland.com/faith-college-book/">book</a> is a compilation of essays written by recent college graduates about their personal experiences.</p>
<p>“The goal is to facilitate dialogue. This is not the sort of book you should look to if you want a really sound biblical exegesis on any topic,” Porter said.” This is people telling their stories and there are parts of my story and I think parts of Lauren’s story too, that we’re not completely proud of.”</p>
<p>The book attempts to tackle highly-debated topics, such as sexuality, alcohol and tobacco use, sexual abuse and most importantly faith, through the use of personal stories. Discussion questions at the end of each chapter aim to help readers explore these topics.</p>
<p>Both Sawyer and Porter graduated in 2012. Sawyer majored in journalism and writing while Porter studied media communications and participated in the Mary C. Dodd Honors program. They submitted their pieces early in the spring of 2013, found out their pieces had been chosen early September, and have been editing since then.</p>
<p>“I had pieces written, but I didn’t decide to submit until the day that submissions were due,” Sawyer said.</p>
<p>Her piece focuses on three parties she attended her last week at IWU.</p>
<p>“Up until some point in college, my idea of the world was that everything was black and white and you could categorize everything as good or bad and anything that was kind of ambiguous made me really uncomfortable,” Sawyer said.</p>
<p>Her stories focus on gray areas like parties, drinking alcohol and having sex, and her difficulty coming to terms with those at IWU.</p>
<p>“It’s really hard to talk about those things at IWU because the rules are really clear. There’s a lot of hiding, there’s a lot of not talking about these things for fear of getting judged or getting in trouble with the school,” Sawyer said.</p>
<p>Looking back on her piece, she has realized that she’s gained a new perspective and understanding of herself and what she was dealing with since being away from school. She’s okay with this though; she feels that it makes the piece authentic to her experience and more relatable for students.</p>
<p>Both Sawyer and Porter said they felt isolated and disillusioned during their time at IWU, and hope that their stories can show students that other people are going through what they went through.</p>
<p>“It felt like because what I was saying differed slightly from what others were saying or what was being said from the pulpit in chapel that my voice wasn’t particularly welcome,” Porter said. “The way that I live out my faith doesn’t look like the way a lot of people on campus think it should look. My faith journey throughout school was largely a process of becoming okay with that.”</p>
<p>Sawyer was very excited to attend IWU because she went to a public high school. She thought everyone would “like the same things” and “have the same interests.”</p>
<p>“That didn&#8217;t happen,” she said. “I got the sense that everyone around me was a better Christian than I was. I felt like somehow I wasn’t as good as my roommates or people across the hall. That kind of started this path of not knowing what it meant for me to be a Christian.”</p>
<p>She said her home church and blogs she read also fostered these spiritual problems, but thankfully, she is on the other side of them.</p>
<p>“It was important for me to go through that because it forced me to ask the questions that got me to where I am now. I find so much life in my faith now and I love my church, which I didn’t ever think would happen, and I feel confident in who I am and who I am to God,” Sawyer said. “All of these things I didn’t feel at IWU and I think it did take that disillusionment to get me to this place.”</p>
<p>Both Sawyer and Porter appreciated their time at IWU, but advocate for more open discussion of these topics.</p>
<p>“I think there’s a lot of benefit in listening,” Porter said. “I think these motifs are not unique to IWU students, I think they are prevalent among millennials and people who are in this demographic and making this transition from adolescence to adulthood.”</p>
<p>Now working at the <a href="http://www.jconline.com/">Journal and Courier</a> in Lafayette, Indiana, Porter enjoyed the editing process because it allowed him to focus on one topic for a longer period of time than a normal news story. He hopes to “find more opportunities like this,” but he recognizes that those are “long-term goals.” He would love to write another essay for a compilation book or magazine.</p>
<p>Porter aims to explore his vocation more, but is limited by job opportunities.</p>
<p>“It’s hard to pursue some of those big, crazy ideas, those big news stories or those big magazine articles that you’d love to pitch when you feel like you need to pay your bills,” Porter said.</p>
<p>Sawyer went to the Seattle School of Theology and Psychology, earning an M.A. in Theology and Culture. She now works as an assistant instructor there, but hopes to continue writing, especially about her experience, confusion, and the questions she faced in college.</p>
<p>“I think those are the most important things that I can be writing about. It feels really good to know that I am actually going to get an audience for that,” Sawyer said. “It’s important for me in my career as a writer, but also feels like I’m going to be able to help people with what I wrote.”</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/iwu-alumni-write-on-their-wrestles-with-faith-in-a-new-compilation-book/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Schulman leads men’s soccer team to success through adversity</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/schulman/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/schulman/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 21:17:11 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mallory Tucker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crossroads League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evan young]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Schulman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keaton albert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mark Castro]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Soccer]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=9005</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the past eight years, Joe Schulman has been an Indiana Wesleyan University assistant men’s soccer coach until recently being named interim head coach after Coach Mark Castro resigned.   Despite the adversity of changing head coaches, the team had a successful season, finishing with an 18-2-0 record, a Crossroads League Tournament Championship and a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the past eight years, Joe Schulman has been an Indiana Wesleyan University assistant men’s soccer coach until recently being named interim head coach after Coach Mark Castro resigned.</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong></p>
<div id="attachment_9008" style="width: 244px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/COACHSCHULMAN.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-9008" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/COACHSCHULMAN-234x320.jpg" alt="Coach Schulman led the men's soccer team on and off the field this season." width="234" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Coach Schulman led the men&#8217;s soccer team on and off the field this season.</p></div>
<p>Despite the adversity of changing head coaches, the team had a successful season, finishing with an 18-2-0 record, a Crossroads League Tournament Championship and a berth in the NAIA National Championship Tournament.</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>Schulman has encountered personal difficulties taking over as head coach, but has sought the Lord through both his own and the team’s trials.</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>“Coach Castro is one of my best friends and I came here to coach with him, but I’m not getting to coach with him now and personally it has been difficult,” Schulman said. “[Taking over as head coach] has taught me many lessons, and anytime we are tested, our faith is tested, or bad things happen to us, our immediate response needs to be worship.”</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>Keaton Albert (jr) said the journey of this season has been challenging.</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>“Personally I would say it’s been tough. It’s like taking a father figure out and putting a new one in with yet another relationship of trust,” Albert said. “However, [Coach Schulman] has done a great job of being personal yet also being a coach.”</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>According to Albert, Schulman has kept the integrity and culture Coach Castro created.</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>“He has taken what Coach Castro built and allowed it to grow instead of doing a complete 180,” Albert said. “When Coach Castro left, he left groundwork, but when Joe came in, he took that groundwork and made it even higher to what it could be, so everything spiritually, tactically, on the field and off the field has become a lot more professional.”</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>Schulman has also sustained Castro’s coaching styles and techniques while taking over as interim head coach.</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>“I had coached with [Castro] for eight years, so coaching wise I am very similar in personality and how I lead the team,” Schulman said. “Because I have been here on and off for eight years, they [the team] know me and I know them, so they haven’t had to relearn a different style of coaching.”</p>
<p>Coach Schulman lives in a townhouse on campus, allowing him to be even more involved in his player’s lives by spending time with them off the field as well. Schulman regularly eats at Baldwin Dining Room, attends chapel and goes to worship events such as The Well.</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>“It’s not really a ministry or anything intentional as much as we hang out a lot together and we share a life together during the season — we call it a brotherhood,” Schulman said. “I get to eat with them, have fun with them and grow with them on and off the field.”</p>
<div id="attachment_9002" style="width: 223px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/MG_6928.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-9002" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/MG_6928-213x320.jpg" alt="Schulman hugs Keaton Albert (jr) after the team's season-ending loss to Vanguard." width="213" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Schulman hugs Keaton Albert (jr) after the team&#8217;s season-ending loss to Vanguard.</p></div>
<p>Schulman encourages the team to maintain their vitality through spiritual strength and drawing closer to God. His number one goal is to develop spiritual discipline and to equip the players for what they will need when they leave IWU.</p>
<p><strong><strong> </strong></strong>Evan Young (so) believes Schulman goes above and beyond by leading team devotions, worship events and as many other venues as he can think of.</p>
<p>“His focus has been to continually challenge us to press into God,” Young said. “We’ve been doing things as a team that will grow us spiritually and from that we have had the attitude to overcome our adversity.”</p>
<p>Schulman proposes team Bible readings where players read a chapter a day, everyday. They have gone through the books of John, Luke, 1 John, 2 John and 3 John and are currently on Ecclesiastes.</p>
<p>“When you don’t have somebody around that you thought you were going to have around all year who was leading your program, it becomes difficult,” Schulman said. “But by the grace of God and by the guys pushing in and buying into the spiritual disciplines, we’ve been able to have success and continue to succeed on the field because of, in my opinion, what we are doing off the field.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/schulman/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Vanguard shocks Wildcats men’s soccer in shootout</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/vanguard-shocks-wildcats-mens-soccer-in-shootout/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/vanguard-shocks-wildcats-mens-soccer-in-shootout/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 04:23:55 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tim Tedeschi]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brandon Gomez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Brian Pautasso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[corey lopez]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crossroads League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dylan Bronkema]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[evan young]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Golden State Athletic Conference]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[J.C. Mahaffey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jacob Beerman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jesus Fregoso]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Schulman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Juan Arellano]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keaton albert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luke Kadillak]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Soccer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[NAIA National Championship]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam kane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thomas Canfield]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tyrone martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Vanguard University Lions]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wildcats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8992</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The No. 4 Indiana Wesleyan University men’s soccer team’s season came to a heartbreaking end as the Vanguard University Lions defeated the Wildcats 4-3 in a shootout after a scoreless draw in the NAIA National Championship opening round Saturday, Nov. 22. Both teams came into the match on win streaks. The Lions had won six [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_9001" style="width: 351px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/MG_6923.jpg"><img class="wp-image-9001" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/MG_6923-480x320.jpg" alt="_MG_6923" width="341" height="227" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Hannah Whelchel.</p></div>
<p>The No. 4 Indiana Wesleyan University men’s soccer team’s season came to a heartbreaking end as the Vanguard University Lions defeated the Wildcats 4-3 in a shootout after a scoreless draw in the NAIA National Championship opening round Saturday, Nov. 22.</p>
<p>Both teams came into the match on win streaks. The Lions had won six straight en route to a Golden State Athletic Conference Championship, while the Wildcats were riding a 17-game win streak into the contest.</p>
<p>It was a back-and-forth affair in the first half as both teams had quality chances for goals. The Wildcats dominated the shot total, though, outshooting the Lions nine to two with five shots on goal. Vanguard goalkeeper Brandon Gomez (fr) made some impressive saves to keep the game scoreless heading into halftime.</p>
<p>The Lions picked up their physicality in the second half, led by midfielder Brian Pautasso (sr). Pautasso was given a yellow card after arguing a foul call with the officials. IWU took eight more shots in the second half while Vanguard did not manage a single shot. Several Wildcats shots were inches away from finding the back of the net, but the score remained tied 0-0 after regulation.</p>
<p>Two overtimes were not enough to settle this game as both teams had several chances but could not score in the overtime periods. The game had to be settled by penalty kicks.</p>
<p>Tyrone Martin (sr) missed the first penalty shot for the Wildcats, followed by a goal from Juan Arellano (so) for the Lions. Keaton Albert (jr), Corey Lopez (jr) and Evan Young (so) matched the scores by goalkeeper Brandon Gomez (fr), Luke Kadillak (jr) and Jesus Fregoso (jr) for the Lions.</p>
<p>With the Wildcats down 4-3 in penalty kicks, Jacob Beerman (sr) missed his shot and Vanguard pulled off the upset.</p>
<div id="attachment_8998" style="width: 296px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/MG_6919.jpg"><img class="wp-image-8998" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/MG_6919-480x320.jpg" alt="_MG_6919" width="286" height="190" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Photo by Hannah Whelchel.</p></div>
<p>Interim Head Coach Joe Schulman said he told his team to keep their heads up despite the shocking loss.</p>
<p>“They’re rock stars for Christ and that’s the most important thing about life so [I told them to] keep pressing in and lead the campus,” Schulman said.</p>
<p>Schulman also praised the senior leadership of Dylan Bronkema, J.C. Mahaffey, Sam Kane, Martin, Beerman and Thomas Canfield.</p>
<p>“The seniors are tremendous,” Schulman said. “All of them.”</p>
<p>The Wildcats men’s soccer team finishes the season with a record of 18-2 and as Crossroads League Champions.</p>
<a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/vanguard-shocks-wildcats-mens-soccer-in-shootout/#gallery-8992-1-slideshow">Click to view slideshow.</a>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/vanguard-shocks-wildcats-mens-soccer-in-shootout/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Mockingjay &#8211; Part 1&#8243; movie leaves audience hungry for more</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mockingjay-part-1-movie-leaves-audience-hungry-for-more/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mockingjay-part-1-movie-leaves-audience-hungry-for-more/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2014 22:58:35 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Lauren Carpenter]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8985</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Going into the theater last night, I had some doubts about “The Hunger Games: Mockingjay &#8211; Part 1,” mainly because I felt that it wasn’t necessary for the movie to be broken up into two parts. Most readers of the books feel the third installment of Suzanne Collins’ The Hunger Games is the most boring one, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Going into the theater last night, I had some doubts about “The Hunger Games: Mockingjay &#8211; Part 1,” mainly because I felt that it wasn’t necessary for the movie to be broken up into two parts. Most readers of the books feel the third installment of Suzanne Collins’ The Hunger Games is the most boring one, and I feel that way as well.</p>
<p>My thoughts definitely changed as I watched the movie.</p>
<p>Director Francis Lawrence added a few more details and scenes to the movie, which I think helped the story. I am glad he made it into two parts, because the previous two movies took too many important details out.</p>
<p>It starts out with Katniss Everdeen (Jennifer Lawrence), now having survived two Hunger Games, underground where District 13 is, confused and in recovery from the Quarter Quell. She is learning that District 12 is destroyed, and her best friend, Gale (Liam Hemsworth), rescued as many people as he could, including her sister, Prim (Willow Shields), and mother (Paula Malcomson).</p>
<p>I enjoyed how “Mockingjay &#8211; Part 1” emphasized the relationship between Katniss and Prim and Katniss and Gale more than the previous films. It showed more of how Katniss is always looking after her little sister, Prim, who she volunteered to replace in the first Hunger Games.</p>
<p>Before seeing this third movie, I was always “Team Peeta” and did not want Katniss to end up with Gale. But these two characters change dramatically in “Mockingjay,” as Peeta (Josh Hutcherson), thinks differently about Katniss and District 13&#8217;s revolt against the Capitol.</p>
<p>In the first two films, Gale had very little screen time, so I hadn’t formed much of an opinion about him. But in this movie, he’s always protecting Katniss and her family, comforting Katniss as she is recovering and showing his real feelings and emotions for her that will make you want to become “Team Gale” — and as always, he looks good doing it.</p>
<p>Throughout this dark and intense movie, two characters provide some comic relief: Haymitch Abernathy (Woody Harrelson), Peeta and Katniss’ mentor, who is now sober for the first time, and Effie Trinket (Elizabeth Banks), their escort, who is trying to transition from Capitol life to living underground in District 13 without her makeup, wigs and elaborate costumes. This is a major change from the book as she is only in it for a short time.</p>
<p>Lawrence portrayed Katniss perfectly in this movie, and I think she has improved with playing this character since the first film. She looked terrible and even a little bit scary — but it was great for the movie. You can see her pain and understand how messed up these Games have made her.</p>
<p>If you are planning to see “Mockingjay &#8211; Part 1” this weekend, I would recommend re-reading or re-watching the end of “Catching Fire” so you remember exactly what is happening because there is not a refresher in the beginning of the movie.</p>
<p>Also, if you are an avid reader of these books like myself, keep in mind it will not completely match up to the book, so you will also be surprised by some of the scenes.</p>
<p>Lastly, be prepared to have your knees to your chest with a nervous feeling in your stomach the entire movie as Katniss and District 13 attempt to bring down the Capitol and save their loved ones — or maybe that was just me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mockingjay-part-1-movie-leaves-audience-hungry-for-more/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Generic: Layers</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/generic-layers/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/generic-layers/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 12:00:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Johnson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8979</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Comic written and illustrated by Danae Keener (sr)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft wp-image-8980" title="This one goes out to all our students from the south." src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Sojourn-Comic-11-Tolerance-WEB-640x246.jpg" alt="Sojourn Comic 11 - Tolerance - WEB" width="600" height="231" /></p>
<p>Comic written and illustrated by Danae Keener (sr)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/generic-layers/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Men’s basketball continues offensive success in rout of Judson</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-basketball-continues-offensive-success-in-rout-of-judson/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-basketball-continues-offensive-success-in-rout-of-judson/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2014 03:03:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Johnson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bethel college]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bob peters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crossroads League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greg Tonagel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jonny marlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Mawhorr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judson University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lane Mahurin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wesley the Wildcat]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wildcats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8967</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The 8-0 Indiana Wesleyan University men’s basketball team reached 100 points for the third straight game Tuesday, Nov. 18 in a resounding 104-71 victory over visiting Judson University (Ill.). The 0-7 Eagles started out the game firing from the three-point line and kept the score close early in the first half, at one point drawing [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The 8-0 Indiana Wesleyan University men’s basketball team reached 100 points for the third straight game Tuesday, Nov. 18 in a resounding 104-71 victory over visiting Judson University (Ill.).</p>
<div id="attachment_8973" style="width: 321px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/DSC_7347.jpg"><img class="wp-image-8973" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/DSC_7347-481x320.jpg" alt="Zac Vandewater (sr) gets ready to shoot a three-point shot." width="311" height="207" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Zac Vandewater (sr) gets ready to shoot a three-point shot. // Photo taken by Becka Roth</p></div>
<p>The 0-7 Eagles started out the game firing from the three-point line and kept the score close early in the first half, at one point drawing to an 11-10 score in favor of the Wildcats.</p>
<p>However, IWU quickly squashed Judson’s hopes of an upset.</p>
<p>By midway through the opening period, the Wildcats had built a 34-17 lead, thanks to playmaking defense and an impressive transition offense attack. On the game, the Eagles turned the ball over 24 times to the Wildcats’ 11, which IWU used to its advantage on the fast break.</p>
<p>It was smooth sailing from then on for the Wildcats. At one point, the lead ballooned to 99-58 before both teams put in their reserves to finish the game.</p>
<p>Lane Mahurin (so) led the Wildcats with 19 points on an ultra-efficient 7-of-8 shooting from the field, and Josh Mawhorr (jr) and Bob Peters (so) added 17 and 16, respectively.</p>
<div id="attachment_8976" style="width: 211px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/WESLEY.jpg"><img class="wp-image-8976" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/WESLEY-240x320.jpg" alt="&quot;Wesley the Third&quot; was unveiled during halftime." width="201" height="268" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;Wesley the Third&#8221; was unveiled during halftime. // Photo taken by Jared Johnson</p></div>
<p>The primary setup man for IWU’s big point-scorers was point guard Jonny Marlin (jr), who dished out 10 assists. Despite playing over 23 minutes, Marlin did not attempt a single field goal in the game.</p>
<p>Wildcats Head Coach Greg Tonagel is pleased with how his team has treated its early-season schedule.</p>
<p>“Coming off of 40-point victories, it’s hard to have good practices,” Tonagel said. “But the team is working hard every day.”</p>
<p>At halftime, the athletic department unveiled a new costume for the school’s mascot, Wesley the Wildcat. The new outfit is the first one for the mascot since 1998.</p>
<p>The Wildcats take the court 7 p.m. next Tuesday, Nov. 25 at Bethel College in Mishawaka, Ind. The contest will be IWU’s first Crossroads League matchup of the season.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-basketball-continues-offensive-success-in-rout-of-judson/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Men&#8217;s soccer repeats as Crossroads League champions</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-soccer-repeats-as-crossroads-league-champions/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-soccer-repeats-as-crossroads-league-champions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 04:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mallory Tucker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crossroads League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dean Nafziger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goshen College]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Schulman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keaton albert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Soccer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam kane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tyrone martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wildcat Field]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wildcats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8955</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Indiana Wesleyan University men’s soccer team won their second straight Crossroads League Tournament Championship on Saturday, Nov. 15 by defeating Goshen College 3-0. The Wildcats scored less than two minutes into the championship game as Keaton Albert (jr) announced his presence at Wildcat Field by scoring a goal with a header past Goshen College’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_8956" style="width: 342px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_2804-2.jpg"><img class="wp-image-8956 " src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_2804-2-225x150.jpg" alt="Keaton Albert (jr) scored two goals for the Wildcats tonight. (photo by Lauren Dafoe)" width="332" height="221" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Keaton Albert (jr) scored two goals for the Wildcats tonight. (photo by Lauren Dafoe)</p></div>
<p>The Indiana Wesleyan University men’s soccer team won their second straight Crossroads League Tournament Championship on Saturday, Nov. 15 by defeating Goshen College 3-0.</p>
<p>The Wildcats scored less than two minutes into the championship game as Keaton Albert (jr) announced his presence at Wildcat Field by scoring a goal with a header past Goshen College’s goalie Dean Nafziger (jr). Tyrone Martin (sr) assisted on the goal.</p>
<p>With eighteen minutes left in the first half, Albert was at it again with a sneaky shot that deflected off of a Goshen defender, raising the IWU lead to 2-0.</p>
<p>“The last two games, I didn’t get the results I was wanting,” Albert said. “I was overjoyed to pull this off for the team.”</p>
<p>IWU came out in the second half with exceptional energy. The Goshen defense struggled to keep up with the Wildcats’ offensive attack. IWU attempted eight shots while Goshen only attempted two.</p>
<div id="attachment_8962" style="width: 326px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_2855.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-8962" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_2855-460x320.jpg" alt="Sam Kane (sr) scored the final goal of the night for the Wildcats. (photo by Lauren Dafoe)" width="316" height="220" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sam Kane (sr) scored the final goal of the night for the Wildcats. (photo by Lauren Dafoe)</p></div>
<p>Sam Kane (so) scored the final goal of the evening to make the score 3-0.</p>
<p>Interim Head Coach Joe Schulman said the team earned one of their season-long goals: a Crossroads League Championship.</p>
<p>“The guys battled hard and earned the win,” Schulman said. “We’ve put in a lot of hard work for months now.”</p>
<p>The Wildcats improve to 18-1-0 on the year and are ranked fifth in the latest NAIA national poll, the best ranking in team history.</p>
<p>The Crossroads League Championship secured the Wildcats’ place in the NAIA National Tournament. The team will play their first round game at Wildcat Field next Saturday, Nov. 22.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-soccer-repeats-as-crossroads-league-champions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
