<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Sojourn</title>
	<atom:link href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com</link>
	<description>Campus News for Indiana Wesleyan University</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 04:16:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
		<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
		<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>http://wordpress.org/?v=4.0</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Men&#8217;s soccer repeats as Crossroads League champions</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-soccer-repeats-as-crossroads-league-champions/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-soccer-repeats-as-crossroads-league-champions/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2014 04:15:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mallory Tucker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crossroads League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dean Nafziger]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Goshen College]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joe Schulman]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[keaton albert]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Soccer]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[sam kane]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[tyrone martin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Wildcat Field]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[wildcats]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8955</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Indiana Wesleyan University men’s soccer team won their second straight Crossroads League Tournament Championship on Saturday, Nov. 15 by defeating Goshen College 3-0. The Wildcats scored less than two minutes into the championship game as Keaton Albert (jr) announced his presence at Wildcat Field by scoring a goal with a header past Goshen College’s [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_8956" style="width: 342px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_2804-2.jpg"><img class="wp-image-8956 " src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_2804-2-225x150.jpg" alt="Keaton Albert (jr) scored two goals for the Wildcats tonight. (photo by Lauren Dafoe)" width="332" height="221" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Keaton Albert (jr) scored two goals for the Wildcats tonight. (photo by Lauren Dafoe)</p></div>
<p>The Indiana Wesleyan University men’s soccer team won their second straight Crossroads League Tournament Championship on Saturday, Nov. 15 by defeating Goshen College 3-0.</p>
<p>The Wildcats scored less than two minutes into the championship game as Keaton Albert (jr) announced his presence at Wildcat Field by scoring a goal with a header past Goshen College’s goalie Dean Nafziger (jr). Tyrone Martin (sr) assisted on the goal.</p>
<p>With eighteen minutes left in the first half, Albert was at it again with a sneaky shot that deflected off of a Goshen defender, raising the IWU lead to 2-0.</p>
<p>“The last two games, I didn’t get the results I was wanting,” Albert said. “I was overjoyed to pull this off for the team.”</p>
<p>IWU came out in the second half with exceptional energy. The Goshen defense struggled to keep up with the Wildcats’ offensive attack. IWU attempted eight shots while Goshen only attempted two.</p>
<div id="attachment_8962" style="width: 326px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_2855.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-8962" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_2855-460x320.jpg" alt="Sam Kane (sr) scored the final goal of the night for the Wildcats. (photo by Lauren Dafoe)" width="316" height="220" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Sam Kane (sr) scored the final goal of the night for the Wildcats. (photo by Lauren Dafoe)</p></div>
<p>Sam Kane (so) scored the final goal of the evening to make the score 3-0.</p>
<p>Interim Head Coach Joe Schulman said the team earned one of their season-long goals: a Crossroads League Championship.</p>
<p>“The guys battled hard and earned the win,” Schulman said. “We’ve put in a lot of hard work for months now.”</p>
<p>The Wildcats improve to 18-1-0 on the year and are ranked fifth in the latest NAIA national poll, the best ranking in team history.</p>
<p>The Crossroads League Championship secured the Wildcats’ place in the NAIA National Tournament. The team will play their first round game at Wildcat Field next Saturday, Nov. 22.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-soccer-repeats-as-crossroads-league-champions/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>ASID hosts 3rd annual Craft Bazaar</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/asid-hosts-3rd-annual-craft-bazaar/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/asid-hosts-3rd-annual-craft-bazaar/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 20:00:50 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sara Williams]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Events]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[American Society of Interior Designers]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Craft Bazaar]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[interior design]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lauren Johns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Marion]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8903</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The American Society of Interior Designers at Indiana Wesleyan University is hosting its third annual Craft Bazaar Nov. 22, calling all crafty people both in the community and on campus to sell their wares in the Commons. The event is the largest fundraiser for the IWU chapter of ASID. Still a young organization at the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The American Society of Interior Designers at Indiana Wesleyan University is hosting its third annual Craft Bazaar Nov. 22, calling all crafty people both in the community and on campus to sell their wares in the Commons.</p>
<p>The event is the largest fundraiser for the IWU chapter of ASID. Still a young organization at the university, ASID remains a mystery to many students, as does the major behind the bazaar: interior design.</p>
<div id="attachment_8951" style="width: 250px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/craft.jpg"><img class="wp-image-8951 size-large" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/craft-240x320.jpg" alt="craft" width="240" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Hope Wittig crochets a scarf to prepare for her booth at the upcoming bazaar. // Courtesy Photo</p></div>
<p>Nationally, ASID exists “to inspire and enrich its members by promoting the value of interior design while providing indispensable knowledge and experiences that build relationships,” according to the official ASID website.</p>
<p>But at the local school level, Lauren Johns (jr), interior design major and president of ASID, said the IWU chapter seeks to connect interior design students with one another, with students at other schools and with design professionals in the state and country.</p>
<p>The group meets every other week for activities and learning about upcoming events both nationally and statewide. Events have included a scavenger hunt in Marion, an ASID and interior design information meeting and now they have their largest event coming up: the annual Craft Bazaar.</p>
<p>Unlike other craft bazaars, the event hosted by IWU’s ASID is cheaper per table, which Johns believes helped fuel the popularity of the event during its first two years.</p>
<p>Tables were $20 until Nov. 12 and are now $25 until Nov. 19, and crafters are allowed to keep all of their profits.</p>
<p>The event also attracts crafters from the Marion community who “may not come on campus for any other reason,” Johns said.</p>
<p>Each year the event has grown, and this year ASID has reserved not only the Commons but Century Dining Room for tables as well.</p>
<p>“I know I’ve heard a lot of people on campus saying that they’re excited for it. I think that because it was so big last year that even more people are going to show up this year,” said Erika Reed (so), interior design and business major.</p>
<p>While the main purpose of the event may be a fundraiser, the craft bazaar also serves as a way to connect with the community, as well as students, who may not otherwise know about ASID or the interior design program.</p>
<p>Any students interested in the organization, the major or hosting a table at the bazaar may visit ASID’s Facebook page: facebook.com/ASIDIWU; or email them: iwuasid@gmail.com.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/asid-hosts-3rd-annual-craft-bazaar/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Men’s basketball overwhelms IU Southeast with balanced scoring</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-basketball-overwhelms-iu-southeast-with-balanced-scoring/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-basketball-overwhelms-iu-southeast-with-balanced-scoring/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2014 02:44:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Johnson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Men's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[bob peters]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Greg Tonagel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiana University Southeast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jacob Johnson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jonny marlin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Josh Mawhorr]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Judson University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lane Mahurin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Luckey Arena]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Men's Basketball]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[nathan bubash]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Zac Vandewater]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8858</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Indiana Wesleyan University men’s basketball team spread the scoring around Friday, Nov. 14 in a dominant 107-68 win at Luckey Arena over visiting Indiana University Southeast. Leading the way for IWU was forward Josh Mawhorr (jr) (17 points, 10 rebounds), Bob Peters (so) (16 points, six assists) and Jonny Marlin (jr) (13 points, eight [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div id="attachment_8884" style="width: 223px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/4.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-8884" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/4-213x320.jpg" alt="photo by Amanda Couser" width="213" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">photo by Amanda Couser</p></div>
<p dir="ltr">The Indiana Wesleyan University men’s basketball team spread the scoring around Friday, Nov. 14 in a dominant 107-68 win at Luckey Arena over visiting Indiana University Southeast.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Leading the way for IWU was forward Josh Mawhorr (jr) (17 points, 10 rebounds), Bob Peters (so) (16 points, six assists) and Jonny Marlin (jr) (13 points, eight assists).</p>
<p>But the key contributors for the Wildcats didn’t stop there.</p>
<p>Lane Mahurin (so) collected 13 points, Zac Vandewater (sr) added 11, Nathan Bubash (so) chipped in 10 and Jacob Johnson (fr) also had 10 to round out IWU’s double-digit scorers.</p>
<p>Although the final score was lopsided, the Wildcats didn’t secure the victory until late in the second half.</p>
<p>IWU led 44-28 at halftime, and IU Southeast closed the gap to 46-34 early in the second half. A 20-3 Wildcats run extended the lead to 66-37, but the Grenadiers didn’t stop fighting. They closed the gap to 79-59 with about 12 minutes to go in the game.</p>
<p>After that, it was all IWU. The Wildcats ended the game on a 28-9 run in which they imposed their will on the weary Grenadiers.</p>
<p>IWU Head Coach Greg Tonagel said the Wildcats played well, and was especially pleased with the balanced scoring.</p>
<p>“We have a lot of guys who can make a lot of different plays,” Tonagel said. “We just have to make sure we let them play their games sometimes and not over-coach them.”</p>
<p>The Wildcats will be back in action next Wednesday at 7 p.m. in Luckey Arena to face Judson University.</p>
<a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-basketball-overwhelms-iu-southeast-with-balanced-scoring/#gallery-8858-1-slideshow">Click to view slideshow.</a>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/mens-basketball-overwhelms-iu-southeast-with-balanced-scoring/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>IWU raising money for Ebola crisis in Sierra Leone</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/iwu-raising-money-for-ebola-crisis-in-sierra-leone/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/iwu-raising-money-for-ebola-crisis-in-sierra-leone/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 14:56:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mallory Tucker]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr. Jim Lo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ebola]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kamakwie Wesleyan Hospital]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sierra Leone]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8851</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[With countless individuals sick and dying, the severity of the Ebola crisis in Sierra Leone has caused The Wesleyan Church to take action. General Superintendent of The Wesleyan Church and founder of the Christian humanitarian program World Hope, Dr. JoAnne Lyon, has reached out to Indiana Wesleyan University in order to raise funds for a [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">With countless individuals sick and dying, the severity of the Ebola crisis in Sierra Leone has caused The Wesleyan Church to take action.</p>
<p>General Superintendent of The Wesleyan Church and founder of the Christian humanitarian program World Hope, Dr. JoAnne Lyon, has reached out to Indiana Wesleyan University in order to raise funds for a project named “IWU Cares.”</p>
<p>The project’s goal is to raise $30,000—enough money to purchase an ambulance for Kamakwie Hospital in Sierra Leone.</p>
<p>Kamakwie Wesleyan Hospital is one of the few hospitals in Sierra Leone the government has put in charge of the Ebola situation. It only has two ambulances to transport the sick and remove the deceased Ebola victims all across Sierra Leone, both of which are old and need replacing, according to Dean of the Chapel Dr. Jim Lo.</p>
<p>The situation has become so intense that the hospital has began to ask workers to use their own private vehicle to transport victims of Ebola.</p>
<p>Lo believes IWU needs to be a part of this project because Christians have a responsibility for other believers who are suffering.</p>
<p>“If we say that we have around 3,000 people that are a part of the residential community and each person gives just ten dollars, we can meet this need very, very quickly,” Lo said.</p>
<p>Lo has reached out to the Director of Alumni Rick Carder to consider asking alumni to give to this fundraiser as well.</p>
<div id="attachment_8853" style="width: 422px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Screen-Shot-2014-11-14-at-9.52.38-AM.png"><img class="size-large wp-image-8853 " src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Screen-Shot-2014-11-14-at-9.52.38-AM-412x320.png" alt="Screen Shot 2014-11-14 at 9.52.38 AM" width="412" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Dr. Jim Lo is encouraging people to donate money to buy this ambulance to help those stricken with Ebola in Sierra Leone.</p></div>
<p>“We are talking about people helping people,” Carder said in an email interview with The Sojourn. “Through the community here at IWU, we believe that each one of us can do something and by combining those gifts we can accomplish so much.”</p>
<p>Lo recognizes not everyone is able to give large amounts of money for causes such as this, but encourages everyone to give by prayer.</p>
<p>“We [IWU] talk a lot about being world changers, and I recognize that not everyone can get out into the world to be the world changers that way, but one of the ways that we can bless other people in the world that are in need is by giving,” Lo said.</p>
<p>An offering for this project will be taken during chapel once a week starting Friday, Nov. 14 until the end of the semester. Student leaders will also be walking through the dorms to raise additional funds.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/iwu-raising-money-for-ebola-crisis-in-sierra-leone/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Editorial: What are the ethics behind swiping and leaving chapel?</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/skipping-chapel/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/skipping-chapel/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2014 04:14:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kayla Thomas]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Editorials]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Front Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[chapel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dr. Jim Lo]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University Chapel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[IWU]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8844</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The new chapel swipe system has been a topic of conversation since the beginning of the 2014-2015 school year, begging the question: is it okay for students to swipe and leave? This question has been argued from both sides. Indiana Wesleyan University has had chapel as a requirement since its founding, more recently with the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">The new chapel swipe system has been a topic of conversation since the beginning of the 2014-2015 school year, begging the question: is it okay for students to swipe and leave?</p>
<p dir="ltr">This question has been argued from both sides. Indiana Wesleyan University has had chapel as a requirement since its founding, more recently with the option to use up to six chapel skips a semester.</p>
<p dir="ltr">This is the first year the integrity of students has been in question in regards to chapel.</p>
<div id="attachment_8846" style="width: 399px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_1290.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-8846 " src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_1290-480x320.jpg" alt="IMG_1290" width="389" height="259" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Students face a decision every time they swipe into chapel.</p></div>
<p dir="ltr">Chapel, which is held at 10:05 a.m., allows students to swipe their ID for chapel credit from 9:45 to 10:15. Over three different chapel days, I stood between two doors and counted how many people swiped their ID and left between 9:50 and 10:05. Over the three observed days, an average of approximately 187 people swiped and left each day. Keep in mind, this number only includes a percentage of the students that left chapel because only two doors were involved in the observation.</p>
<p dir="ltr">So how does The Office of the Dean of the Chapel feel about the number of students choosing not to stay for the chapel services?</p>
<p dir="ltr">“We decided to go with the one-swipe [system] because we wanted to show that we trusted our students,” Dean of Chapel Jim Lo says. “We went to the administration and then on to the cabinet and I presented that I believe that most of our students really are trustworthy individuals, so we wanted to give them more freedom.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">The major point Lo is trying to make is that the one-swipe system was not put in place because it was easier, faster or cheaper. While all of these things might be true, the one-swipe system was put in place to grant the students more responsibility, trust and freedom. I think that, as a student body, we are so focused on the thrill of getting away with something, that we have chosen to throw away the newfound trust and responsibility we have been entrusted with by the university.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The argument on one side is that swiping and leaving is a lie. You are not correctly representing Christ because you are allowing someone to believe something that is not true.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“We are a Christ-centered university, therefore we should strive to be more like Christ.” Timothy Loney (fr) said. “By intentionally deciding to not be at chapel, and yet swiping into chapel, you are not living up to the call of this university and more importantly, the call of Christ.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">The counter argument is, “What if I have homework? Or a big test? Can’t I praise God through excellence in my school work?” This is a valid argument, but we must remember to be respectful of the speakers who have given up their time to come share God’s word, as well as the students who want to hear it.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“This is an integrity issue, I have spoken to guest speakers, the thing that distracts many of them is when they see the students getting up and walking out,” Lo said. “It’s been very painful for them to see that because a message is already being given.”</p>
<p dir="ltr">While swiping and leaving can be viewed as an integrity issue, we must remember that we are still one body in Christ, even though attending chapel is now a personal decision, that does not give us the right to judge those who chose not to attend.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“Those who choose to stay for chapel shouldn’t look down on those who choose not to go. Just because we have chosen not to go does not mean that we are less of a Christian than they are,” Hannah Guerin (so) says. “Those who look down on others for doing what only they think is wrong might be the ones who need to be at chapel the most.”</p>
<p>While the actual percentage of students leaving chapel services is relatively low, it is important to keep the issue of integrity at the forefront of our minds. Skipping chapel might give us a “thrill”, but while we are missing out on chapel, we just might be missing out on God.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/skipping-chapel/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>3</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;A Midsummer Night&#8217;s Dream&#8221; Review</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/a-midsummer-nights-dream-review/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/a-midsummer-nights-dream-review/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 20:08:22 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ali Cravens]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Arts & Entertainment]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Front Page]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Reviews]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA["A Midsummer Night's Dream"]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Black Box Theatre]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Braden Hunt]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Phillippe Performing Arts Center]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Shakespeare]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Theatre Guild]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8834</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[The Indiana Wesleyan University Theatre Guild will be having its first performance of “A Midsummer Night’s Dream” 7:30 this evening, Nov. 13. With IWU’s unique approach to this play, these Grecian lovers, bumbling laborers and mischievous fairies bring Shakespeare’s comedy to life in the school’s own own Phillippe Performing Arts Center. The play begins outside [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">The Indiana Wesleyan University Theatre Guild will be having its first performance of “A Midsummer Night’s Dream” 7:30 this evening, Nov. 13. With IWU’s unique approach to this play, these Grecian lovers, bumbling laborers and mischievous fairies bring Shakespeare’s comedy to life in the school’s own own Phillippe Performing Arts Center.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The play begins outside the Black Box Theatre. In an ideal performance, the cast would perform this first part of the play in the main lobby of the PPAC, but on nights when the auditorium is being used, as on the evening I saw it, the beginning takes place in the hallway right outside the Black Box.</p>
<div id="attachment_8837" style="width: 367px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_1904.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-8837   " src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_1904.jpg" alt="IMG_1904" width="357" height="268" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Braden Hunt (sr) plays King Oberon and Sharla Ball (sr) plays Queen Titania.</p></div>
<p dir="ltr">With the audience standing, the bright lighting, the whirring of the drinking fountain and the green “Exit” signs and metal doors, it was difficult to suspend our belief and transport ourselves into Athens, Greece, when everything around us screamed “we are in a hallway.” The awkwardness of the unusual surroundings seemed to reflect in the actors as well, as they seemed slightly uncomfortable in the hallway setting. I can only hope that when it gets to be performed in their intended place of the main lobby that things come off a little bit better.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Right away, even in this awkward beginning part, Gloria Billingsley (fr) stood out in her character of Hermia. She was so delightfully animated that not even the glaring lighting or hum of the drinking fountain could upset her performance.</p>
<p dir="ltr">And boy did it put a smile on my face to see the next group of actors: Peter Quince and his band of “rude mechanicals,” as Puck refers to them. In the script, where some of the mechanicals with lesser lines seem to not be very distinct from one another, each of these characters had their own quirky mannerisms and personalities, which made them just so fun to watch.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Chelsea Haskett (so) especially stood out among them as Flute. With her knee-buckled walk and her tucked-in chin, she was the most amusing to watch. For such few lines, especially in the beginning, she really grabbed the audience’s attention.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Braden Hunt (sr), too, demanded our attention amidst the group of rude mechanicals, though his part was quite a bit more overt than Flute’s. As Bottom, Hunt was hilarious, boisterous and outrageous. With his wide movements and exaggerations of character, he also was a delight to see perform.</p>
<p dir="ltr">After about the first 30 minutes spent in the hallway, we moved to take our seats in the Black Box, or the “enchanted forest.” I was a little disappointed in the set, however, as it didn’t really look like an “enchanted forest” to me at all. There were no trees or plants to be seen. While the appearance wasn’t ideal, the actual design of the set was very unique and intricate.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The design of the set possessed some very cool features that allowed for fun, surprising touches, and very interesting and creative entrances, exits and interactions on stage. So while they used the design of the set very well and very creatively, it simply didn’t come off as an enchanted forest.</p>
<div id="attachment_8836" style="width: 339px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_1889.jpg"><img class="wp-image-8836    " src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_1889.jpg" alt="IMG_1889" width="329" height="247" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Morgan Hause (fr) plays Puck.</p></div>
<p dir="ltr">The music didn’t help with that either, however, as it sounded more like African tribal music, more appropriate for “The Lion King” than an enchanted forest in Greece.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The actors portraying the fairies of this enchanted forest wore masks throughout the play, which was a great way to give them a more magical-like appearance and set their world apart from the humans’.</p>
<p dir="ltr">While I’m not sure about the use of masks in theatrical performances as a whole, since they cover up half of the face, which is a major tool for actors and a way in which the audience connects with them and sees their acting, the masks were well-done and the actors used them very well.</p>
<p dir="ltr">Puck, one of these masked beings, didn’t come off quite as I was expecting him to, seeming more like King Oberon’s creepy servant than the freewheeling, mischievous sprite that I thought him to be.</p>
<p dir="ltr">There was a 10-minute intermission before the last half hour of this two and a half hour long play. This last thirty minutes, which consisted of the play-within-a-play put on by the rude mechanicals, while fun, dragged on quite slowly.</p>
<p dir="ltr">The Theatre Guild did some really interesting, unique things with this play. As with any performance of “A Midsummer Night’s Dream,” it requires complex and intricate settings, costumes and carefully-crafted character interactions. And as with any Shakespearean play, it is no small feat to put on. The Theatre Guild and everyone who was involved in the play did a great job and really made it their own, a unique artistic creation to IWU that I recommend everyone see.</p>
<p>Showings are 7:30 p.m. Nov. 13-15 and Nov. 20-22 and 2 p.m. Nov. 15 and 22 in the Black Box Theatre in the PPAC. Admission is $7 for students, $10 for IWU employees and senior citizens and $12 for adults.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/a-midsummer-nights-dream-review/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Generic: Creed</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/generic-creed/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/generic-creed/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 12:00:28 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Johnson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Comics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Other]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8829</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Comic written and illustrated by Danae Keener (sr)]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignleft  wp-image-8831" style="font-size: 13px;" title="If I had a nickle every time I heard this question during chapel... Considering this day's economy I really wouldn't be all that rich." alt="Sojourn Comic 10 - Creed - WEB" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Sojourn-Comic-10-Creed-WEB-640x246.jpg" width="576" height="221" /></p>
<p>Comic written and illustrated by Danae Keener (sr)</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/generic-creed/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Small class, essential skills: UNV-170 teaches students effective research skills</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/small-class-essential-skills-unv-170-teaches-students-effective-research-skills/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/small-class-essential-skills-unv-170-teaches-students-effective-research-skills/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 02:11:40 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Brooke Eber]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[On Campus]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[front1]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Indiana Wesleyan University]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jackson Library]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Research Class]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8824</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Where can I find the information I need? How do I find that information quickly? How will I know if it is credible? What questions do I need to ask &#8211; and answer &#8211; about my topic? These are the types of questions the class UNV-170: Introduction to Library Research will answer. One of the [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Where can I find the information I need? How do I find that information quickly? How will I know if it is credible? What questions do I need to ask &#8211; and answer &#8211; about my topic?</p>
<p>These are the types of questions the class UNV-170: Introduction to Library Research will answer. One of the smallest classes at IWU, the class usually runs between four and six students, giving students a lot of personal attention.</p>
<div id="attachment_8825" style="width: 393px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/photo-1.jpg"><img class=" wp-image-8825" src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/photo-1-426x320.jpg" alt="photo 1" width="383" height="288" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">UNV-170 welcomes all students interested improving their research skills.</p></div>
<p>“What we try to do with the course is lay the foundations of information in general and how information has grown and how evaluation has or has not changed over the centuries,” Library Director Sheila Carlblom said. “We’re really trying to give people the fundamentals.”</p>
<p>Carlblom and Reference Librarian Laura Kelsey teach the class, with Carlblom as the main professor.</p>
<p>“It’s very practical for the student. We show you a lot of tips and tricks that you aren’t going to gather on your own,” Kelsey said. “A lot of students comment after they’ve had the class that they wish they had had the class earlier in their college careers.”</p>
<p>The class will teach students how to evaluate sources and databases to find out what’s worth using in their papers. It will also focus on what resources to use in certain situations. The class has been offered every semester since 2007, but did not run this semester due to low registration.</p>
<p>Carlblom and Kelsey would like a class size of about 10 or 12.</p>
<p>“We are prepared for 24, but you would get far less individualized attention,” Carlbom said. “We said we could do 24 because so many professors said they wanted their students taking this.”</p>
<p>Carlblom finds the individual attention very helpful to students, as they are able to bring their own research topics to class.</p>
<p>“We’re not here to make extra work. What we would rather do is the students have something in play, which is why its almost easier for a sophomore or junior, or even a senior, because they have so many research projects they need to get done,” Carlblom said. “We don’t want to create more work, but better work.”</p>
<p>Both Carlblom and Kelsey find the course does more than just teach students how to be successful in college.</p>
<p>“Even if you’re not going to [graduate] school, these are concepts you can continually apply in lifelong learning,” Kelsey said. “Sometimes students wing it in preparing for classes and just get the information that’s necessary, but in your personal life doing personal research thats not what you’re going to want.”</p>
<p>“All of life is dependant on asking the right questions. It’s important to understand that these are the questions we need to ask to do due diligence in every area of life and when it comes to our health and what we put in our bodies, that’s important stuff,” Carlblom said, using the example of advertised “miracle” diet pills to show how important it will be out of college to do your research.</p>
<p>For the 2015 spring semester, UNV-170, a one credit hour class, will be held Mondays from 2:20-3:15 p.m.</p>
<p>“We are more than willing to work with whatever students are willing to come our way,” Carlblom said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/small-class-essential-skills-unv-170-teaches-students-effective-research-skills/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tedeschi&#8217;s Take: Referees</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/tedeschis-take-referees/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/tedeschis-take-referees/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 01:22:53 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Tim Tedeschi]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sports Columns]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Referees]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8803</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[When’s the last time you’ve heard someone say, “The referees called a really fair game today?” That’s what I thought. I don’t know if I’ve ever heard anyone say that. Referees. Blue. Ump. Zebras. Whatever nickname you use, you’re probably using it to complain. When they make decisions that go against your team, they’re wrong [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">When’s the last time you’ve heard someone say, “The referees called a really fair game today?”</p>
<p>That’s what I thought. I don’t know if I’ve ever heard anyone say that.</p>
<p>Referees. Blue. Ump. Zebras. Whatever nickname you use, you’re probably using it to complain.</p>
<p>When they make decisions that go against your team, they’re wrong even if the replay confirms their call. When they make a lot of calls, they are ruining the game by slowing it down.</p>
<p>Most sports fans, no matter the sport and no matter how successful their team is, think that the referees are against them. Many fans even have specific stories of how a referee’s mistake cost them a game or even a championship.</p>
<p>I’m guilty of referee bashing as well. Nearly every game I watch I find myself criticizing the referees at some point.</p>
<p>It’s the most thankless job in all of sports. Referees are dragged through the mud for bad calls and get little to no praise for making the right decisions.</p>
<p>But I think it’s time we give referees a break. They are people whose job is to make split second decisions that affect teams, fan bases and sometimes the entire country. And with instant replay, anyone and everyone in America can point out their mistakes. How would you perform under that pressure?</p>
<p>So often we make referees public enemy number one, but they’re really just professionals trying to do their job to the best of their ability. Are they going to make bad calls? Yes. Will the majority of their decisions be right? I think so.</p>
<p>So let’s try to be more gracious to referees. I know it’s easier said than done, but I’m going to make an effort to not criticize officiating and appreciate the good work referees do.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/tedeschis-take-referees/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
		<item>
		<title>Portera&#8217;s caring attitude aids volleyball team</title>
		<link>http://www.iwusojourn.com/portera/</link>
		<comments>http://www.iwusojourn.com/portera/#comments</comments>
		<pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2014 01:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Jared Johnson]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Sports]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Women's Athletics]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Candace Moats]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Crossroads League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[kylie portera]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sam Elkin]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sarah Collicot]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Volleyball]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://www.iwusojourn.com/?p=8814</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[It’s pretty easy to tell that Indiana Wesleyan University Volleyball Middle Blocker Kylie Portera (so) is a nursing major. “I could tell within the first week [I met her] that she was a nurse,” Outside Hitter Sarah Collicott (so), one of Portera’s roommates, said. “Just through the way she treats people and cares for people, [&#8230;]]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p dir="ltr">It’s pretty easy to tell that Indiana Wesleyan University Volleyball Middle Blocker Kylie Portera (so) is a nursing major.</p>
<p dir="ltr">“I could tell within the first week [I met her] that she was a nurse,” Outside Hitter Sarah Collicott (so), one of Portera’s roommates, said. “Just through the way she treats people and cares for people, she’s really level-headed in a lot of situations.”</p>
<div id="attachment_8815" style="width: 404px" class="wp-caption alignleft"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Portera.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-8815" alt="Kylie Portera (#7) brings her nurse's attitude to the volleyball team." src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/Portera-394x320.jpg" width="394" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Kylie Portera (#7) brings her nurse&#8217;s attitude to the volleyball team.</p></div>
<p dir="ltr">“Kylie has a personality that is perfect for a nurse,” Head Coach Candace Moats said. “She sees peoples’ needs and she cares for them.”</p>
<p>Portera’s caring personality and hard work on the court have been instrumental in the volleyball team’s success this season. Through Nov. 12, she ranked fourth on the team with 238 kills. Now, the Wildcats are entering the final stretch of a very successful season in which they won the Crossroads League regular-season title for the third straight year.</p>
<p>But ironically enough, Moats and Portera actually formed their relationship in the midst of defeat.</p>
<p>“I was at a club tournament the summer after my junior year [of high school] and I was playing a game and I had heard from someone that there was going to be someone from IWU there,” Portera said. She added her team was not playing well that day.</p>
<p>“It was one of those games where, at the end, you talk as a team and then everyone just splits out and goes by their parents,” Portera said.</p>
<p>Moats didn’t care that Portera’s team was playing badly. She saw something special in Portera that she knew she liked.</p>
<div id="attachment_8820" style="width: 223px" class="wp-caption alignright"><a href="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_22041.jpg"><img class="size-large wp-image-8820" alt="Portera goes up for a block." src="http://www.iwusojourn.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/IMG_22041-213x320.jpg" width="213" height="320" /></a><p class="wp-caption-text">Portera goes up for a block.</p></div>
<p>“Kylie’s team was not doing well at the time, but I saw her constantly staying focused and talking to her teammates, telling them to keep their heads up,” Moats said. “Her coach was getting somewhat angry, and she was keeping her poise. And I just was so impressed with how she handled this whole disappointing experience. For her, it seemed like it was bigger than just the game.”</p>
<p>Moats approached Portera after the game. Portera was surprised that anyone would want to talk to a member of her team after its subpar performance.</p>
<p>“I just spoke truth to her and said, ‘I watched you and you inspired me,’” Moats recalled.</p>
<p>From that moment, Portera said she knew she had to look at IWU as a possible college to attend. One month later, she visited, and she was sold right away. She decided she would attend the university as a nursing major and play on the volleyball team the next fall.</p>
<p>Portera’s nursing mentality showed itself immediately to her teammates.</p>
<p>“I could tell that she really had a heart for God with everything, whether through her actions or words spoken,” said Defensive Specialist Sam Elkin (so), who now also rooms with Portera.</p>
<p>Portera didn’t play much her freshman year because the Wildcats already had All-American Middle Blocker Kristine Egebrecht (alumna ’14), but she’s had a breakout campaign this fall.</p>
<p>“[Kylie’s] gotten a lot more confident this year, and she’s taking a lot more responsibility as she finds herself as more of a contributor on the court,” Moats said.</p>
<p>But Portera hopes Wildcats fans will watch her team for more than just good volleyball &#8211; she wants them to see a glimpse of the love of Christ.</p>
<p>“Now I know I don’t [treat my teammates] perfectly,” Portera said. “But I hope when people watch our games, they see that the way we work together on the court is glorifying to God.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			<wfw:commentRss>http://www.iwusojourn.com/portera/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
		<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
